<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: french | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/french/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-30T00:12:24+10:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel-James Wynyard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[christmas 2016 is key]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/17/christmas-2016-is-key/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-17T12:57:09+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/17/christmas-2016-is-key</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Even though I&rsquo;ve already posted today, this is an amendment. Today Jake sat me down at cibo espresso to write out my resume to write out my resume so I can get myself a new position. I&rsquo;ve been really down just recently after the departure from DPC.</p>

<p>He gets it. Jake really gets me, or does such a great job pretending that I feel safe and secure. Whilst working on my resume he comes over and pops this down in front of me.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/08/17/IMG_4884.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;christmas 2016&rsquo; &lsquo;christmas 2016&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Wow&hellip;a Christmas ornament! But not just anything - a keepsake! You want to spend Christmas with me! Does that mean we&rsquo;re going to be a family? Are our dreams going to be a reality for the two of us?</p>

<p>Hello world, Jake and Danijel, are a family. We are slowly getting there. It will be another year or three, but we&rsquo;re going to be our own family one day!</p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[can you see deeper?]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/17/can-you-see-deeper/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-17T12:57:09+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/17/can-you-see-deeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simply looking down, it&rsquo;s a shopping trolley. With few ingredients. Ricotta, cheese, pasta, broccolini, bread crumbs, milk, celery, and a few other things. It&rsquo;s really so simple, but is it? Can you see deeper into this image?</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/08/17/IMG_4891.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;can you see deeper?&rsquo; &lsquo;can you see deeper?&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s our shopping trolley. It&rsquo;s out life. If I told you this is only something simple, it&rsquo;s this moment, that we are here in the name of love, would you see deeper? It&rsquo;s just today. It&rsquo;s just this moment. We&rsquo;re doing our shopping, together. Ever seen your parents shopping together? Or young couples who&rsquo;ve maybe just started their life together? Or how about and old couple with more wrinkles than you can count on your fingers and toes?</p>

<p>I present to you here, one of my most favourable photos from the time we&rsquo;ve spent together. Here and now, today, we are shopping for our groceries - together. We&rsquo;ve decided on meals for a week ahead, convened, agreed, argued, and resolved. Then moved forward.</p>

<p>The act of grocery shopping in itself is quite simple. It&rsquo;s no more than an action of survival at the base of it all. Nothing more, nothing less. An action to plan out a survival plan to nourish our bodies so we can seemingly pass through another period of time. Weekly, monthly, fortnightly? How often do you shop? Do you shop? Are you shopping for yourself, your partner, your family, your friend? Anyone at all?</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re about to embark on an adventure between the two of us as we move through another period of transition. Bringing the aspect of weekly meals from separation into a single unified action. Sometimes I cook, sometimes Jake cooks.</p>

<p>Did I write about earlier my blue recipie book? Maybe not. I don&rsquo;t remember all the articles in this blog and what I spoke out from time to time, so I can forget where I&rsquo;m up to!</p>

<p>TL;DR - When I decided Jake was the person I&rsquo;d be spending the rest of my life with, I went out and bought a blue feint lined Moleskin book. Here was to be the recipes that celebrated the history of our life together. From all my experience so far, I had the tools I needed to bring joy to Jake&rsquo;s life through food. Sometimes I&rsquo;m wondering what I&rsquo;m really good at. Is it just making breakfast in bed with a kiss on his forehead? Or is it the warm chicken and sweet corn soup <em>(with special ingredients he would kill me if he found out were in there)</em> when Jake isn&rsquo;t feeling well, so he gets better soon? I don&rsquo;t know. I just know that for many years I&rsquo;ve never fully embraced the kitchen, whether it was a lack of interest or a lack of ambition - but now I feel home is in the kitchen when I know that I&rsquo;ll be making us a meal to share.</p>

<p>But I don&rsquo;t bake. That is solely Jake&rsquo;s forte. My baking skills are limited to setting the fire alarm off and everyone needing to evacuate the building.</p>

<p>The next time you go grocery shopping, stop for a moment and look into your basket, trolley, bag - whatever! Look at it, and see where you really are in life, where you&rsquo;re going, and what you&rsquo;re doing. Don&rsquo;t miss the small things because they are parts of a much greater image.</p>

<p>A jigsaw cannot be complete if you miss 1 piece.</p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[that's my card!]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/13/thats-my-card/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-13T22:45:08+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/13/thats-my-card</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the card that Jake bought me for my birthday! 😍</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/08/13/IMG_4805.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;my birthday card&rsquo; &lsquo;my birthday card&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[can't stop the felling]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/07/cant-stop-the-felling/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-07T22:40:36+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/07/cant-stop-the-felling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Has anyone heard that song &ldquo;Can&rsquo;t Stop The Feeling&rdquo; by Justin Timberlake? Jake loves that song, because it annoys me&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/08/07/IMG_4653.jpg" width="800" height="450" title="&lsquo;jake loves this song&rsquo; &lsquo;jake loves this song&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>And he&rsquo;s proud to sing it aloud&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/08/07/IMG_4655.jpg" width="800" height="450" title="&lsquo;jake loves this song&rsquo; &lsquo;jake loves this song&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>&hellip;god, I love him!</p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[smile 'cos someone loves you]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/04/smile-cos-someone-loves-you/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-04T12:31:39+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/04/smile-cos-someone-loves-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2016/08/04/IMG_4588.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="&lsquo;so much love&rsquo; &lsquo;so much love&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
