<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: french | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/french/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-29T14:21:18+10:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel-James Wynyard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[can you see deeper?]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/17/can-you-see-deeper/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-17T12:57:09+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/17/can-you-see-deeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simply looking down, it&rsquo;s a shopping trolley. With few ingredients. Ricotta, cheese, pasta, broccolini, bread crumbs, milk, celery, and a few other things. It&rsquo;s really so simple, but is it? Can you see deeper into this image?</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/08/17/IMG_4891.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;can you see deeper?&rsquo; &lsquo;can you see deeper?&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s our shopping trolley. It&rsquo;s out life. If I told you this is only something simple, it&rsquo;s this moment, that we are here in the name of love, would you see deeper? It&rsquo;s just today. It&rsquo;s just this moment. We&rsquo;re doing our shopping, together. Ever seen your parents shopping together? Or young couples who&rsquo;ve maybe just started their life together? Or how about and old couple with more wrinkles than you can count on your fingers and toes?</p>

<p>I present to you here, one of my most favourable photos from the time we&rsquo;ve spent together. Here and now, today, we are shopping for our groceries - together. We&rsquo;ve decided on meals for a week ahead, convened, agreed, argued, and resolved. Then moved forward.</p>

<p>The act of grocery shopping in itself is quite simple. It&rsquo;s no more than an action of survival at the base of it all. Nothing more, nothing less. An action to plan out a survival plan to nourish our bodies so we can seemingly pass through another period of time. Weekly, monthly, fortnightly? How often do you shop? Do you shop? Are you shopping for yourself, your partner, your family, your friend? Anyone at all?</p>

<p>We&rsquo;re about to embark on an adventure between the two of us as we move through another period of transition. Bringing the aspect of weekly meals from separation into a single unified action. Sometimes I cook, sometimes Jake cooks.</p>

<p>Did I write about earlier my blue recipie book? Maybe not. I don&rsquo;t remember all the articles in this blog and what I spoke out from time to time, so I can forget where I&rsquo;m up to!</p>

<p>TL;DR - When I decided Jake was the person I&rsquo;d be spending the rest of my life with, I went out and bought a blue feint lined Moleskin book. Here was to be the recipes that celebrated the history of our life together. From all my experience so far, I had the tools I needed to bring joy to Jake&rsquo;s life through food. Sometimes I&rsquo;m wondering what I&rsquo;m really good at. Is it just making breakfast in bed with a kiss on his forehead? Or is it the warm chicken and sweet corn soup <em>(with special ingredients he would kill me if he found out were in there)</em> when Jake isn&rsquo;t feeling well, so he gets better soon? I don&rsquo;t know. I just know that for many years I&rsquo;ve never fully embraced the kitchen, whether it was a lack of interest or a lack of ambition - but now I feel home is in the kitchen when I know that I&rsquo;ll be making us a meal to share.</p>

<p>But I don&rsquo;t bake. That is solely Jake&rsquo;s forte. My baking skills are limited to setting the fire alarm off and everyone needing to evacuate the building.</p>

<p>The next time you go grocery shopping, stop for a moment and look into your basket, trolley, bag - whatever! Look at it, and see where you really are in life, where you&rsquo;re going, and what you&rsquo;re doing. Don&rsquo;t miss the small things because they are parts of a much greater image.</p>

<p>A jigsaw cannot be complete if you miss 1 piece.</p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[smile 'cos someone loves you]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/04/smile-cos-someone-loves-you/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-04T12:31:39+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/04/smile-cos-someone-loves-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2016/08/04/IMG_4588.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="&lsquo;so much love&rsquo; &lsquo;so much love&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[303 by the seas]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/31/303-by-the-sea/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-31T12:07:18+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/31/303-by-the-sea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, scrolling through Yelp! looking for a new place to go eat at and came across the venue <a href="https://www.yelp.com.au/biz/303-by-the-sea-henley-beach">303 By The Sea</a>. We&rsquo;ve been there already but had to sit outside because of my indecisiveness. So now we&rsquo;re back and we got a nice table at the back of the room.</p>

<p>The lines are long, it&rsquo;s loud, people are sighing, you&rsquo;re really waiting a while to get served - but who can question the quality of the food being served!? It looks amazing.</p>

<p>Jake wanted a hashbrown, eggs, mushrooms and bacon - just simple. Well, apparently not. After discovering the hashbrowns are a meal unto themselves and can&rsquo;t be served with the condiments I asked for, the chef came over and disagreed with my request. As I asked her, I don&rsquo;t mind how much this is going to cost me - find a suitable price and let me have what I want.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/31/IMG_4497.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;waiting impatiently&rsquo; &lsquo;waiting impatiently&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>It took them a while to get his food out to us. I really was quite impressed with the quality of my food, but I can&rsquo;t really rave about the experience as a whole. We took to Facebook to make comments about the quality of the experience and endured a tirade from the Madam Chef on Facebook. Sheesh! I don&rsquo;t know what the problem was. Maybe she was having a bad day?</p>

<p>All in all, it&rsquo;s a great place, but I think it&rsquo;ll be some time before we come back here. Maybe in the summertime instead?</p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[never enough flowers]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/19/never-enough-flowers/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-19T12:02:35+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/19/never-enough-flowers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flowers, because I love you. These will wilt and die, but the short time they are with you, are just a fraction of your life. Appreciate them for the time we have their beauty. As I appreciate the beauty that is you.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/18/IMG_4107.jpg" width="777" height="800" title="&lsquo;roses mean remember&rsquo; &lsquo;roses mean remember&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[food, football, fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/07/food-football-fun/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-07T11:35:04+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/07/food-football-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So who would have ever thought that I&rsquo;d be intersted in sport? Not me, that&rsquo;s for sure. It&rsquo;s Friday and Jake&rsquo;s organised something for us to do. What exactly I&rsquo;m not sure. But why would I care? As long as I&rsquo;m spending time with him I just know that my life is the greatest achievement.</p>

<p>We ended up first at a restaurant on North Tce that I hadn&rsquo;t been to, but eyeing off since I got back to Adelaide. Argentinian influenced steak house/tapas bar. Service was a bit below par, but the waitress lightened up the mood. Food was incredibly juicy and I really liked it.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.yelp.com.au/biz/la-boca-bar-and-grill-adelaide">La Boca</a> is generally pretty busy from what I&rsquo;ve observed each time I&rsquo;ve been past so it was great to finally get in here and have a look at the place.</p>

<p>Heading down to the football we grabbed a drink each and went down to our favourite spot. It&rsquo;s not the first time I&rsquo;ve come to the football with Jake and I feel like he&rsquo;s opened my eyes to appreciate the simpler things in life I&rsquo;ve learned to reject. Maybe I should pick a team and get a season pass for the two of us? That would make a nice surprise and we&rsquo;ll finally start to accumulate elements in our life which belong to nobody else but ourselves.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/07/IMG_3770.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;standing on the hill&rsquo; &lsquo;standing on the hill&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After the football match we went down to the carpark to find some Pokémon to build up our Pokédex more. Bored with this we went on to the Alpine Winter Village on North Tce. What do we see apart from crap food and llamas? Ice arena! Fuck yes!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/07/IMG_3798.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;boys on the ice&rsquo; &lsquo;boys on the ice&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Poor Jake fell over totally whilst I was busy filming a selfie video. He fell just out of the frame and I had tears literally flowing freely as I keeled over to laugh instead of going over to help him. What kind of a boyfriend am I? The worst kind!</p>

<p>Before the night was over we stopped in at a little photo booth van to get 4 black and white selfies - the old style selfie - in a film strip. I love this photo so much of us. I&rsquo;ve never had a chance to do something cool and fun like this all my life and secretly always been jealous of the people that keep images like this in their wallet. Thank you Jake. This was an amazing night. You&rsquo;re the greatest.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/07/IMG_3979.jpg" width="600" height="800" title="&lsquo;photo booth fun&rsquo; &lsquo;photo booth fun&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
