<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: french | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/french/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-03T07:40:30+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel James]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[avoir (to have)]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/24/avoir-to-have/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-24T23:03:06+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/24/avoir-to-have</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like être, avoir is an irregular verb.</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left;"> avoir </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> to have </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> j'ai (=je ai) </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> I have </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> tu as </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> you have </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> il/elle a </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> he/she has </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> nous avons </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> we have <em>(n)</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> vous avez </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> you have <em>(n)</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> ils/elles ont </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> they have <em>(m/f)</em> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>Il a un voitre <em>(m)</em> > He has a bus<br/>
J'ai une montre <em>(f)</em> > I have a watch</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[être (to be)]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/23/etre-to-be/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-23T09:36:37+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/23/etre-to-be</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The most common verb is être (to be).</p>

<p>&ldquo;être&rdquo; is an irregular verb whatever the tense is. Here is the conjugation in the present:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left;"> être </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> to be </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> je suis </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> I am </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> tu es </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> you are </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> il/elle est </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> he/she is </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> nous sommes </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> we are <em>(n)</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> vous êtes </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> you are <em>(n)</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;"> ils/elles sont </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"></td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> they are <em>(m/f)</em> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>Nous sommes á la plage <em>(f)</em> > We are at the beach<br/>
Je suis sur la autobus <em>(m)</em> > I am on the bus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[tasmania is an experience!]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/20/tasmania-is-an-experience/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-20T15:14:09+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/20/tasmania-is-an-experience</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sitting on my Jetstar flight back to Sydney, QF77, retrospectivey I have mixed emotions about the hospitality of people from Tasmania. In this hand it had to be one of the worst places for anyone to experience a welcome in all of Australia. And that includes Sydney. Disgusting. What happened to the good framework that this country was built upon? My travelling companion Grenouille (🐸), may not have been able to understand the dymanics of three particular situations that played out at hand but I certainly did! On the other hand we were greeted like a lost stranger that had a reservation waiting to be fulfilled.</p>

<p>I arrived at <a href="http://www.hotbartinternational.com.au">Hobart Internaitional Airport</a> and was taken back at how small this place is. Really? This is an international travel destination? It&rsquo;s not even half the size of the old Adelaide International Airport before it was revamped a few years ago. Weird.</p>

<p>Getting off the plane my first messages from Grenouille warm and fuzzy until I was told the car licence was forgot and left behind. LOL! Double LOL! So Grenouille went back towards his place of stay and I resorted to my UK licence. Yes, scary as it may be for a lot of people, I do have a valid international licence and it won&rsquo;t be taken away from me. Yet. 😝</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First up was Thank you for the welcome at <a href="http://www.redspot.com.au">RedSpot</a>, your assistance was amazing! 5-Stars! ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️ You were friendly, welcoming, and extremely helpful. I would just like to mention you with a shout-out here on my blog. Thank you! 👍🏻</p>

<p>Bringing it right down to a shorter post, we travelled around Tasmania on Mercredi, Jeudi, Vendredi and Samedi.</p>

<h3>Day 1 Wednesday <em>(jour un mercredi)</em></h3>

<h4>Sorell Fruit Farm</h4>

<p>Amazing little farm a short stint out of Hobart. Bit annoyed that we couldn&rsquo;t go into the farm with just a single bucket between the two of us. We didn&rsquo;t really need two buckets <em>(large punnets)</em> between us to collect 3 apples, 2 pears and a handful of strawberries. Was fun! Grenouille couldn&rsquo;t pick a strawberry to save a life, but decided to steal mine to make the punnet look nice and plump. Pears were small but juicy. Nashi pears to be exact. Apples were yellow-ish in colour but nice. Strawberries were almost all gone but having worked on the Beerenberg Farm myself a few years back I knew how to pick them. The staff were a bit touchy with some of the Asian tourists who just wanted to walk around the orchards to look whilst one of them picked them. So they too were forced to buy a bucket each. Maybe they could fix this business model?</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160217.iPhone6Plus.121409.jpg" width="600" height="800" title="&lsquo;Sorell Farm Strawberries&rsquo; &lsquo;My catch from the day!&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Tasmanian Devil Park</h4>

<p>This was a little bit of a disappointment. It&rsquo;s the Tasmanian Devil Park Unzoo. It&rsquo;s not a &ldquo;zoo&rdquo; per se, but they help in the breeding and conservation of the Tasmanian Devil. Unbeknown to most, the Tasmanian Devil suffers from a cancer that is transmitted by blood - much like the HIV virus. And also like the HIV virus, we don&rsquo;t know where it came from <em>(the cancer)</em>. My favourite part was going out to the Kangaroos to play, watching Quolls devour an animal carcass and the feeding of the Tasmanian Devil. So voracious! Both of them! Who ever thought a Quoll was such a savage eater! 😰</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160217.iPhone6Plus.163226.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;Kangaroo Not Impressed&rsquo; &lsquo;Kangaroo Not Impressed&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Eaglehawk Neck Historic Site</h4>

<p>Eaglehawk Neck had some natural formations that really take a moment to let sink into the mind. The Tessellated Pavement Slate Reserve down on the beach shore looked like tiles laid by man from above, upon closer inspection we reaslised it was natural formations from erosion of the stone over years from the ocean.</p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160217.600D.9874.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Tessellated Pavement&rsquo; &lsquo;Tessellated Pavement Slate Reserve&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Coal Mines</h4>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t take my camera with me, so I have no real images of this place. It&rsquo;s a long walk of scattered ruins and a quarry that goes deep in to the ground. An eerie Silent Hill effect wavers over this point of interest. If you&rsquo;re easily scared, don&rsquo;t go here. We did see this little cute echidna and Grenouille managed to snap an amazing shot of a short-billed echidna!</p>

<p><img src="/images/GC.20160217.iPhone6.115154.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;Short-Billed Echidna as caught by Grenouille&rsquo; &lsquo;Short Billed Echidna caught by Grenouille&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Port Arthur</h4>

<p>Resting on Port Arthur for the night, everything closes at 8pm. Literally, everything. Grenouille and I got a châlet at <a href="http://www.portarthurvillas.com.au">Port Arthur Villas</a> and they took us in late at night without much ado. A bit pricey for my liking, but what the hell, we&rsquo;re on holidays afterall! Wonderful room with amazing views. Awesome breakfast in the morning too!</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160217.iPhone6Plus.091545.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Continental Breakfast at Port Arthur Villas&rsquo; &lsquo;Continental Breakfast at Port Arthur Villas&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Before we turned it in we headed down the road to a recommendation from our innkeeper to the <a href="http://www.portarthur.org.au">Port Arthur Historic Site</a> bistro restuarant. Greeted by the lovliest old queen <em>(yasss, kween 🙌🏻)</em> who tended to our whims and needs. Heck, he even gave up 4 of his own cigarettes because no shops where open when we were leaving! 5-Stars! ⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️⭐️ Dinner was an amazing salmon dish served on a bed of noodles. Wonderful!</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160217.iPhone6Plus.203923.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Crispy Skin Salmon served on Soba Noodle Base&rsquo; &lsquo;Crispy Skin Salmon served on Soba Noodle Base at Port Arthur Historic Site Felons Restaurant&rsquo;" ></p>

<h3>Day 2 Thursday <em>(jour deux jeudi)</em></h3>

<h4>Callington Mill - Oatlands</h4>

<p>After a brief stop for petrol at the town before, I ducked in quickly to the local candy store leaving Grenouille wondering where I was! 😁</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160218.iPhone6Plus.142116.jpg" width="600" height="800" title="&lsquo;Danijel in the candy store&rsquo; &lsquo;Cochon in a candy store&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>On we headed to see the local windmill which was easy to see from afar, just proving tricky to find up close. The Callington Mill is a working Gregorian windmill built in 1837. That&rsquo;s all I can say about it. It&rsquo;s not really that exciting, and there&rsquo;s nothing to tell about it. 😕 To make the story more exciting, there were <code>#wasps</code> nearby.</p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160218.600D.0145.800res.jpg" width="533" height="800" title="&lsquo;Callington Mill&rsquo; &lsquo;Callington Windmill&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Being a little hungry we headed into town to try the Pancake and Crepe Shop. Without going into it too much here on this page, please feel free to head over to <a href="https://www.yelp.com.au">Yelp!</a> to check out my review <a href="https://www.yelp.com.au/biz/pancake-and-crepe-shop-oatlands">here</a>. In short, it was crap. Everything about this place was crap. I&rsquo;d love to know that in time, people are able to go here and give a higher rating than I was.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160218.iPhone6Plus.132555.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;&rsquo; &lsquo;Not very nice berry pancakes&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Spring Vale Vineyards - Cranbrook</h4>

<p>Whenever I think of Vineyards, I think of rich snobby cunts or those that like to think they&rsquo;re rich snobby cunts - the complete opposite here! Greeted warmly and with welcome that reminds me of my father inviting people to the dinner table to share a meal. We tried every type of white and red on the menu walking away with a 750mL of white and smaller bottle of red. I&rsquo;ll keep these as a memory to share with Grenouille in a month from now when I see him on Adelaide. We had a quick tour of the vineyards and just enjoyed a casual stroll amongst the vines. Lovely.</p>

<h4>Coles Bay</h4>

<p>Unfortunately I can&rsquo;t find my pictures from this location and will have to go back through my Lightroom catalog to see where they went. I hope I haven&rsquo;t lost them! 😰 I took some amazing photos here and almost fell off a cliff getting them! 😡 Coles Bay gives you surmountable views of the ocean.</p>

<h4>Wineglass Bay</h4>

<p>Wineglass Bay is a bit of a hike up the mountain. You need to purchase access for your car at the local centre on the way down or risk getting a fine. At least the car ticket allows up to 8 people to access the park and climb up. I met a young couple who were taking <em>(or trying to)</em> romantic photos of one another. Being a complete sucker to help people capture memories the way their imagination sees it, I took her camera and snapped a few wonderful shots of them wit hthe view of the water behind them. She was a bit stuck up. But meh. 😏</p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160218.600D.0160.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Wineglass Bay&rsquo; &lsquo;Wineglass Bay, TAS&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I quickly also snuck in an image of these Asian tourists sitting down to rest. When Grenouille and I were reviewing photos he asked me _&ldquo;Do you know these people? Are they your friends?&rdquo; LOL, no dear. I love you because you&rsquo;re so silly sometimes. 😘 I&rsquo;m a photographer in the making, I capture memories.</p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160218.600D.0166.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Random Asian Tourists&rsquo; &lsquo;Random Asian Tourists&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Bicheno &amp; Penguin Tour</h4>

<p>Aren&rsquo;t penguins just the darnest little things? Theys&rsquo;re so adorable and the firs thing that comes to mind when I say penguin in most kids my age is Pengu! We arrived in the town of Bicheno but unfortunately as I hadn&rsquo;t booked far enough in advance like Grenouille asked me to we didn&rsquo;t rest here for the night. We had to continue on to St Helens - much further down the way!</p>

<p>The town of Bicheno is quite small, almost just a tourist destination. We had dinner at <a href="http://thesealifecentre.com.au">Sea Life Centre</a> and unfortunately it&rsquo;s the second place that I was absolutely disgusted at the level of service and hospitality received. Not for myself and Grenouille, but for this poor Asian tourist family of 3 <em>(trois personnes)</em>. It wasn&rsquo;t anything short of dispicable. I&rsquo;m yet to write up a review on Yelp! about this place, but believe me it won&rsquo;t be anything short of the truth. The food here was also a bit of a let down. Fish of the Day was Broadfish and really was a reflection of their patronage.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160218.iPhone6Plus.200417.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Fish of the Day - Broadfish&rsquo; &lsquo;Fish of the Day - Broadfish&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After dinner we moved over to the <a href="http://www.bichenopenguintours.com.au">Bicheno Penguin Tour</a> carpark and bought our tickets ready to board bus no. 4 <em>(autobus numero quatre)</em> to head off and see these darling little birds. Unknown to me, these are the same penguins on Granite Island off the coast of Victor Harbour, SA.</p>

<p>The tour was licensed by some commission and they help in the repopulation of penguins in Australia. As penguins are light sensitive animals, photography of any kind wasn&rsquo;t allowed so I couldn&rsquo;t snap any photos for the two of us. We were supposed to write to them asking for photos but I&rsquo;ve forgotten to do this at the time of writing so when this post gets re-edited, I&rsquo;ll have to add a pic of what we saw to this article. Grenouille has the pics already. I&rsquo;m just a banana! <em>(Je suis un banane!)</em> 🍌</p>

<h4>Tidal Waters Resort St Helens</h4>

<p>Wow&hellip;remember people to book your accomodation WELL in advance of travel, else end up like us travelling for an hour to the town a few clicks down the road for a night stay! I don&rsquo;t have much to say about this place except the accomodation was great, the in-house services was amazing and if you ever want to get married give this place a look. They have all the services you&rsquo;d expect from a 4&#189; star accomodation rating. Beautiful! And the best part wasn&rsquo;t even having to move the car to the carpark. The night manager let us keep it slap-bang in the middle of the driveway! We were up early enough to have breakfast but didn&rsquo;t make it in time. 😁 A fantastic recommendation from the said manager in the morning started our journey the very next day, jour trois vendredi!</p>

<h3>Day 3 Friday <em>(jour trois vendredi)</em></h3>

<h4>Mohr and Smith</h4>

<p>Following the recommendation from our place of stay, we left our car in place and walked the 8 mins to the shop. Yes, this was much against my desire to walk but what choice did I have? I am the lazy Cochon (🐷) and he is the Grenouille! So around the corner we did walk with a quick stop to grab some cash <em>(rub your chin when you say that aloud, it has a good effect!)</em> and to be honest - it looked like a Mercerella Bros venue than somewhere you&rsquo;d expect to have brunch. First impressions from the outside blew me away the moment we stepped through the door and greeted by the wonderful man serving coffee at the bar who politely told us to discover a place we feel comfortable and he&rsquo;ll be right over.</p>

<p>We grabbed a menu at the door as we walked in so that means I could start to devour the food mentally without having to wait hand and foot on the service of the staff. In this case the only staff member in sight!</p>

<p>I went with the French Toast 🇫🇷 served with caramelised apples and marscapone. This was nothing short of amazing! 😍 The bread was lightly toasted, brioche in style, with a sufficient drizzle of flavour begging you to take more. It was like the devil had created a dish to keep the gluttons being glutonous!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016.0219.iPhone6Plus.103404.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;French Toast&rsquo; &lsquo;French toast, caramelised apples &amp; marscapone cheese&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Wonderful fast service, friendly atmosphere, a real Sydney <em>chic</em> vibe to be found here right in the heart of Tasmanian country. This place deserves its 5-star rating on Yelp! If I could move this to anywhere, it would be Pyrmont in Sydney. Perfect all round! Try it if you ever get to pass through on the way to anywhere!</p>

<h4>Bay of Fires</h4>

<p>Bay of Fires <em>(named so in 1773)</em> is an amazing secluded beach stretching from Binnalong Bay right up around the coast. It took us a few tries to get close enough to the rocks we could see in the distance and listening to some of my favourite tracks on the iPhone and then braving the wilderness barefoot to get there, but we did in the end. Poor Grenouille really is delicate and couldn&rsquo;t stand on the hot Australian sand or rough ground without hurting his poor soles! I should have been nice enough to pick him up, but in my usual I was too busy laughing or well, just laughing.</p>

<p>Apart from the wasps, and nearly being dragged out to the ocean trying to catch an amazing shot of the water splashing against the foot of the orange hued rocks, there is nothing here short of paradise.</p>

<p>Rather than talk about it, look over these images. I&rsquo;ve also uploaded an album to my <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/danijeljames">Flickr</a> account that you can look at with the hi-res images of all these pics and more.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/02/25094235811_906f3a3c40_z.jpg" width="640" height="155" title="&lsquo;Bay of Fires Panorama&rsquo; &lsquo;Bay of Fires Panorama&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0198.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Birds on a Broken Jetty&rsquo; &lsquo;Birds on a broken jetty at Binalong Bay near the Bay of Fires&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0202.800res.jpg" width="533" height="800" title="&lsquo;Another view of Broken Jetty&rsquo; &lsquo;Another view of Broken Jetty at Binalong Bay near the Bay of Fires&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0229.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Feet in Binalong Bay&rsquo; &lsquo;Feet in Binalong Bay&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0241.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Binalong Bay Beach&rsquo; &lsquo;Binalong Bay at Bay of Fires&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0269.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Water splash&rsquo; &lsquo;Water splash against rocks at Binalong Bay&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0304.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;Orange hued rocks at Bay of Fires, Tasmania&rsquo; &lsquo;Orange hued rocks at Bay of Fires, Tasmania&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0316.800res.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;View from rocks at Bay of Fires, Tasmania&rsquo; &lsquo;View from rocks at Bay of Fires, Tasmania&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0318.800res.jpg" width="533" height="800" title="&lsquo;Orange hued rocks with wasps&rsquo; &lsquo;Orange hued rocks, wasps, Bay of Fires, Tasmania&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160219.600D.0342.800res.jpg" width="533" height="800" title="&lsquo;Last jetty I made Grenouille stop at&rsquo; &lsquo;This is the last jetty I made Grenouille stop at before heading back to St Helens for lunch&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After the Bay of Fires, we headed back to St Helens to grab some grapes, local cheeses, crackers and soda water before our trip back to Hobart. Unfortunately, as luck would have it, we didn&rsquo;t rest where we expected for the night and ended up in a town about 30min west of Hobart called Tynwald at an amazing home-run cottage called Tynwald Willow Bend Estate.</p>

<h4>Tynwald Willow Bend Estate</h4>

<p>Unfortunately I have no photos of the estate itself, but they can be found on <a href="https://images.google.com">Google Images</a>. Greeted by <em>(what I believe is the husband)</em> of the lady that I spoke to on the phone, I was ushered through the manor to the dining room, the reading room, the the breakfast room and then to a book on the <a href="http://www.hobartcity.com.au/hobart/hobart_events/salamanca_market">Salamanca Markets</a>. She has a frined that runs the bee was stall closest to the entrance. Grenouille and I dropped off our things, had a spa, shower, got dressed then headed to town for dinner. If you&rsquo;re ever in the area, give it a go. It&rsquo;s wonderful. Very old fashioned and run the way a manor should and you&rsquo;d not want or need for anything as the family-run estate has it all. It is a little behind the times but you&rsquo;ll love the feel if you miss your grandma&rsquo;s house from when you were a child. Re-living it as an adult gives you a sense of when things were simpler and people were innocent.</p>

<h4>Rockwall Bar and Grill</h4>

<p>How this place is a bar is beyond me. You walk to the end of Salamanca Pl and see a small sign hinged above a door giving indication of where it is. Walk through a sliding electronic glass door and almost immediately you&rsquo;re greeted by friendly and warm staff from all angles asking you for a drink whilst you wait and what was the reservation. This a no-bullshit kind of venue! Immediately after getting your wine <em>(we took the bottle of some local Tasmanian label)</em> you notice the ambient atmosphere is signature to the venue - this place has some intense class!</p>

<p>Before getting through 2 sips we&rsquo;re ushered to our table and sat down between a couple of where about to have their first child and a couple who&rsquo;ve been together for so many years the lines on their faces showed all the good times, the bad times and all the times in between. Discussions on one side of the table ranged from talk of holidays taken to holidays to be taken. Such extremes to create a balance.</p>

<p>Grenouille and I ordered the Pumpkin Risotto and onion rings. It hadn&rsquo;t even occured to me that maybe this kind of dish would normally be sold in America, UK and Australia predominately with maybe a few locations scattered around the globe in tow! None the wiser what it was until I explained.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160219.iPhone6Plus.205458.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Pumpkin Risotta&rsquo; &lsquo;Pumpkin Risotto&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After dinner we headed off back to Tynwald to rest the night before heading off back to see MONA and the Salmanaca Markets in the morning.</p>

<h3>Day 4 Saturday <em>(jour quatre samedi)</em></h3>

<h4>Salamanca Markets</h4>

<p>Quoted as <em>&ldquo;The best markets in Australia&rdquo;</em> is not a title short of being deserved! A complete immersion in the siggts, sounds, flavours, action and colour that makes Tasmania unique can be found here. Every Saturday from 8:30 until 15:00 is where the action is. The highlight of my visit? This coffee cup, of course!</p>

<p><img src="/images/20120220.iPhone6Plus.103456.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Glorious coffee cup&rsquo; &lsquo;Awesomely glorious coffee cup&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>MONA - Museum of Old and New Art</h4>

<p>Before I headed down this week to join Grenouille I spoke about my intended journey with the Chief of Operations Executive Assistant and she told me to take some time to see the Museum of Old and New Art <em>(MONA)</em>. Luckily, I took that advise. Sure, some of the art is weird or something I can&rsquo;t consider to be art, but I implore this above all - visit MONA if you visit Tasmania for the sake of exploring art not artists.</p>

<p>I could write more about this but it&rsquo;s better to leave you with this single image from the artwork that helped me decide to ask Grenouille to add this to our itinerary.</p>

<p><img src="/images/20160220.iPhone6Plus.115201.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;vagina art MONA&rsquo; &lsquo;vagina art at MONA, Hobart&rsquo;" ></p>

<h4>Hobart International Airport</h4>

<p><em>&ldquo;All good things must come to an end&rdquo; -Geoffrey Chaucer</em> are the only words that come to mind when we arrived here. This destination in our journey across Tasmania means that Grenouille and Cochon were about to go separate ways on separate journeys.</p>

<p>We had our last meal together and off he flew to his next leg as did I back to Sydney. So here I am, on flight Jetstar flight QF77 going back over the memories that should not be forgotten lest left off the pages that make up the story of this world.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/tasmania-trip/20160220.iPhone6Plus.0358.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Our last meal in Hobart&rsquo; &lsquo;Last meal together in Hobart at the Airport&rsquo;" ></p>

<hr />

<p>Dear Hobart,</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t know I was thirsty until I tasted your wine with love from France. Now I know I&rsquo;m dying without another sip.</p>

<p>Regards,
Danijel James</p>

<hr />

<p>In short - don&rsquo;t eat at the following places until they improve their customer service to a standard:</p>

<ul>
<li>Pancake &amp; Crepe Shop, Oatlands, TAS</li>
<li>Sea Life Centre, Bicheno, TAS</li>
</ul>


<p>Everywhere else is OK 😉</p>

<p><code>#EditedPost</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sentence structure]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/14/sentence-structure/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-14T18:08:27+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/14/sentence-structure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is the same as in English. Most sentences are built on the same template:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center;"> Sujet </th>
<th style="text-align:center;">Verbe </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> Complément </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> Translation</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center;"> La pluie </td>
<td style="text-align:center;"> frappe </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> sur les carreaux. </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <em>The rain hits windows-panes.</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center;"> Les arbres </td>
<td style="text-align:center;"> perdent </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> leurs feuilles. </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <em>The trees are losing their leaves.</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center;"> Caroline </td>
<td style="text-align:center;"> cueille </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> des pommes. </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> <em>Caroline picks some apples.</em> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[un, une, des (articles indéfinis)]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/13/un-une-des-articles-definis/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-13T17:58:54+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/13/un-une-des-articles-definis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>un</strong>, <strong>une</strong> and <strong>des</strong> are the French equivalents for <strong>a</strong> and <strong>some</strong>.</p>

<p>un <em>(m)</em> and une <em>(f)</em> are used for persons/things.</p>

<p>Plural form of all objects is des <em>(pl)</em> regardless of whatever gender is occupied.</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center;"> Anglais </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> Français </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center;"> a </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> un <em>(m)</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center;"> </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> une <em>(f)</em> </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center;"> some </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> des <em>(pl)</em> </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>un légume <em>(m)</em> > a vegetable<br/>
une mer <em>(f)</em> > a sea</p>

<p>des légumes <em>(m,pl)</em> > vegetables<br/>
des mers <em>(f,pl)</em> > seas</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
