<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photography | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-12T09:12:03+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel-James Wynyard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[all i know is he loves him]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/11/all-i-know-is-he-loves-him/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-11T13:17:27+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/11/all-i-know-is-he-loves-him</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I met Ralf, Jake&rsquo;s dog since he was a kid. Ralf is 9 years old now :-)</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/11/20160611.ralf2.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;ralf &amp; jake&rsquo; &lsquo;ralf &amp; jake&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I know they belong together because they both have the same attitude and facials. Could you ask for anymore proof that a dog resembles its' master ?</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/11/20160611.ralf4.jpg" width="800" height="450" title="&lsquo;all i know is he loves him&rsquo; &lsquo;all i know is he loves him&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Apart from the kind nature of this <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shar_Pei">Shar Pei</a>, I cannot fathom what makes him just so adorable ! All I know, is Jake loves him and that touches me softly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[soufflé round 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/08/souffle-round-2/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-08T16:22:36+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/08/souffle-round-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got home from a night at Jake&rsquo;s <em>(awww&hellip;.😍😘😍)</em> and Tom was eagerly awaiting me to make soufflé for him.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/08/20160608.iPhone6SPlus.2537.800.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;doing what i do best, whipping&rsquo; &lsquo;doing what i do best, whipping&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The results ? Of course they&rsquo;re a success ! Jake called me a <a href="https://tenplay.com.au/channel-ten/masterchef">MasterChef</a> 😉</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/08/20160608.iPhone6SPlus.2539.800.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;MasterChef Danijel beats with love&rsquo; &lsquo;MasterChef Danijel beats with love&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to make food for Jake for the rest of his life. I think my experience with the kitchen and food is enough to bring to our relationship that something that will last our lifetime spent together. I do hope he knows how much I love him. He&rsquo;s the sunshine on a rainy day for me.</p>

<p>Did Tom like the soufflé, naturally of course. Whipped cream and all !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[breakfast is served]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/07/breakfast-is-served/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-07T11:39:02+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/07/breakfast-is-served</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Who wants breakfast at the Haus of Danni-Jel ? You do, bitches :P</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/07/20160607.iPhobne6SPlus.2427.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;breakfast deluxe&rsquo; &lsquo;breakfast deluxe&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello paddy's lantern]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/02/hello-paddys-lantern/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-02T10:42:32+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/02/hello-paddys-lantern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Arriving back here in Adelaide on March 3rd this year, one of the first things I did was take to social platform <a href="http://www.grindr.com">Grindr</a> to get a feel from everyone where the best coffee shops were. Yesterday I was talking to Jakey and asked him if he&rsquo;s ever heard of <a href="http://paddyslantern.com.au">Paddy&rsquo;s Lantern</a>. Unfortunately not, and I did leave it to the last two of places to still check out.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t remember who referred me this venue, but thank you, whoever you are ! It was an absolute delight !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/02/1438068476190.png" width="800" height="500" title="&lsquo;paddys lantern&rsquo; &lsquo;paddys lantern&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Nested in the suburban district of Adelaide hidden amongst the old houses at 219 Gilbert Street, this little niche cafe can be found.</p>

<p>The food was amazing, coffee was amazing and to top it off - the service was brilliant !</p>

<p>I picked myself the <em>2 Fried Eggs w/ Spicy Relish on Sourdough Toast</em> and at only $13 this was a total bargain ! You can&rsquo;t go wrong with the perfectly cooked eggs, rustic sourdough, and devilish homemade spicy relish. Mmmmm !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/02/20160602.iPhone6SPlus.091706.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Eggs, Spicy Relish, Sourdough&rsquo; &lsquo;Eggs, Spicy Relish, Sourdough&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I also got my standard large size soy latte, no sugar as this is what I really came for. Keeping up standards, I had it served in a takeaway cup. I was a little taken back by the service of being offered my cup still on a saucer, and not just handed to me.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/02/20160602.iPhone6SPlus.091446.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;soy latte takeaway&rsquo; &lsquo;soy latte takeaway&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The print on the cups is faded, but even so it&rsquo;s still so cute ! 😊 I can&rsquo;t delay my observations of a full bodied flavour with amazing texture steamed perfectly and no burning with a lasting aroma - wow ! This has to be <em>the</em> coffee in Adelaide. They deserve the 4&frac12; stars awarded to them on <a href="http://www.yelp.com.au/biz/paddys-lantern-adelaide">Yelp!</a> too !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/02/20160602.iPhone6SPlus.093056.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;second coffee to go thnx&rsquo; &lsquo;second coffee to go thnx&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re in the area and you want amazing breakfast, please head on down there, bring your partner, work colleagues or a friend and enjoy the simplicity of the atmosphere, the warmth of the service, the spectacular tastes of the products and most importantly - experience it for yourself !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[car wash and lamb dinner]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/01/car-wash-and-lamb-dinner/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-01T10:40:35+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/01/car-wash-and-lamb-dinner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh no, what&rsquo;s he done ? Jake&rsquo;s given me his car for the day !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.095132.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;uh oh spaghetti-o&rsquo; &lsquo;uh oh spaghetti-o&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>This poor man is always tired, stressed or sleeping. What do you think I&rsquo;m gonna do today ? That&rsquo;s easy. I&rsquo;m gonna wash his car for him and surprise him at the end of the day 😄</p>

<p>I went to the RepCo or whatever it&rsquo;s called near my house and got some supplies. When I was young I had a weekend job that saw me travelling to car yards each Saturday morning and I&rsquo;d wash the cars. It wasn&rsquo;t how many cars were washed per hour, it was here&rsquo;s $150, go was as many cars as you can per hour for 3 hours. Not bad when you&rsquo;re 14 !</p>

<p>Men like pink, right ? Well, I&rsquo;m a man and I&rsquo;m not afraid of pink, and I love the bubblegum smell of the detergent I picked for this job too!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.110357.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;sweet like bubblegum&rsquo; &lsquo;sweet like bubblegum&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>So how do I go with this job ? Fantastic darling, absolutely fantastic. I remember Jake saying to me that the one time he goes to wash his car, and so does the whole of Adelaide. LOL This is going to be perfect opportunity for me to do something for him, and him alone. It&rsquo;s not a present. It&rsquo;s not something I&rsquo;ve made. It&rsquo;s something I can do for the sake of doing it for him because this is what real love is about. It&rsquo;s what you can do for that person to make their life a little better. Call it a miracle, if you will, I try to perform a miracle each day for Jake. That&rsquo;s always on my agenda.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.113541.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;wash wash wash&rsquo; &lsquo;wash wash wash&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>To say that washing his car was worth it would be an understatement. It saved Jake so much time and effort; and now it&rsquo;s one less thing that he can worry about.</p>

<p>But he&rsquo;s coming over for dinner tonight, <em>yeah, it&rsquo;s not like we&rsquo;re never getting married or anything, so may as well show him that I can cook, and well sic.,</em> so what do I make him ? I know&hellip;his favourite dish - Lamb ! Best part is, I&rsquo;ve not cooked lamb for anyone &hellip; EVER !</p>

<p>Obviously it was good when you see someone staring on at their food wanting do devour it, &lsquo;eh ?</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.2160.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;can i have my lamb now?&rsquo; &lsquo;can i have my lamb now?&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I think our collaborative effort to make dinner, <em>Jake made the veggies, I made the sauce just for his palate and the lamb to my own style,</em> and it came out pretty swish if you ask me !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.2170.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;a dish well made&rsquo; &lsquo;a dish well made&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Would you say that was a great dinner Jake ? Oh what&rsquo;s that ? 10/10 ? Lee Lin Chin would be proud ! 5 Stars !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.202632.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;i love this man&rsquo; &lsquo;i love this man&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
