<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photography | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-21T00:10:23+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel James]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fun with HDR]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/17/fun-with-hdr/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-17T15:45:49+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/17/fun-with-hdr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Grenouille and I were walking along Lagon Beach and he was just out in front of me. Not wanting to be part of my public images <em>(boring, I know right?)</em> I can&rsquo;t post his face, but he did jump as he stepped onto a slippery rock and I couldn&rsquo;t help but take this shot as my trusty 600D was poised and ready to fire.</p>

<p><img src="/images/DJW.20160217.600D.9902.HDR_sml.jpg" width="200" height="200" title="&lsquo;&rsquo; &lsquo;Genouille HDR Silver&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The full-res image can be found on Flickr here: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/danijeljames/24851378680/">DJW.20160217.600D.9902.HDR</a></p>

<p>I love this style of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-dynamic-range_imaging">HDR</a> that I developed as I explored earlier images <em>(again, with Grenouille as the subject)</em>. I take the original image and apply my Adelaide Filter, Fireworks T2, and then Fireworks T2 with greyscale. The result combination gives me this silver effect to the image and brings out the high grain and contrast that is normally not visible to the naked eye.</p>

<p>Unfortunately a side-effect can be the final image will give any skin a &ldquo;rippened&rdquo; effect and all the small contours, spots and stains on your skin will show up.</p>

<p>Personally, I love this. I feel it truly brings out the character of the subject and lets you see them for what they really are. I&rsquo;m tired of seeing images in magazines of models sprawled across the glossy pages exposing their overlay of beauty. Real beauty comes from within. It&rsquo;s not something that can be measured by scienctific <em>(FR:scientifique)</em> methods but by the beat of one&rsquo;s own heart.</p>

<p>Essentially, I think he&rsquo;s beautiful in all the images I don&rsquo;t publish. I keep them safe and secure as I&rsquo;m asked. Grenouille is beautiful on the inside as this seeps through his skin to the outside too.</p>

<p>Retrospectively, HDR images are a combination of 3 - underexposed, exposed and overexposed. Alternatively you can use high colour capture, low colour capture and middle colour capture. This allows you to expose all the areas of an image and blend them into a single frame. I don&rsquo;t like the standard HDR except when I need to bring out the sky against a darkly lit forground. Even then I have other tricks that I use in Lightroom to aid me with the final resolution.</p>

<p>Bottom line, if you&rsquo;re too often relying on hardware or software to take amazing photos, you&rsquo;re clearly not trying hard enough. Try, try and try again. Without practice you can&rsquo;t believe in yourself. Once upon a time I sucked too. In fact sometimes I pour over my images and want to discard them becasue they&rsquo;re ugly and resort to Lightroom. When I get the final result I just delete them from my Catalog. Nobody wants a Adobe-edited image. It&rsquo;s so fake!</p>

<p>Keep up the good work and eventually you&rsquo;ll get there! 😉🍷</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomorrow to Tasmania]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/16/tomorrow-to-tasmania/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-16T22:59:32+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/02/16/tomorrow-to-tasmania</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow I&rsquo;m headed to Tasmania to join Grenouille 🐸. I don&rsquo;t know how I ever agreed to this wild adventure, but I&rsquo;m sure it&rsquo;s gonna be crazy and most probably full of awesome opportunities to capture the essence that is Tasmania.</p>

<p>I really should be going to sleep soon but I figured sitting here that I can quickly dart across the road to McDonald&rsquo;s and grab a chocolate sundae before laying down to sleep.</p>

<p><img src="/images/16-02-2016_sundae_inception.jpg" width="200" height="200" title="&lsquo;&rsquo; &lsquo;McDonalds Large Sundae&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I expect there to be some amazing shots available on this island!</p>

<p><code>#EditedPost</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
