<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photography | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-09T01:10:11+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel-James Wynyard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[happy mothers day]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/happy-mothers-day/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-08T10:42:21+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/happy-mothers-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To the strongest woman I&rsquo;ve ever known. Raising three boys, all ratbags 😁 Our mother, is the bone of our spines, keeping us straight and true. She is our blood, making sure it runs rich and strong. She is the beating of our hearts. I cannot imagine a life without her. To the world you are a mother, to your three ratbags you are our world. Happy Mothers Day Mum 😘💐🌟</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/05/08/14910844667_bae4756d72_c.jpg" width="629" height="800" title="&lsquo;my mother&rsquo; &lsquo;my mother&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[getting an awesome wallpaper]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/06/getting-an-awesome-wallpaper/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-06T03:34:52+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/06/getting-an-awesome-wallpaper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having made a promise that I would go back and get a photograph of the sunrise to make a wallpaper for the <a href="http://www.apple.com/au/shop/buy-iphone/iphone6s">iPhone 6S Plus</a>, I finally got back up to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Lofty">Mount Lofty</a> this morning and managed to capture some interesting shots.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I didn&rsquo;t think to bring my other lenses with me when I came up here so I was limited to my <a href="https://www.canon.com.au/en-AU/Personal/Support-Help/Product-Help/Camera-Accessories/Camera-Lenses/EF-S%2018-55mm%20f35-56%20IS%20II">18-55mm</a> lens, but managed to capture some nice shots.</p>

<p>The sun comes up pretty quickly too ! Honestly, it&rsquo;s not there one moment, then suddenly she&rsquo;s peeping her head over the horizon and then&hellip;</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="https://media.giphy.com/media/7offL3yehzrKU/giphy.gif">https://media.giphy.com/media/7offL3yehzrKU/giphy.gif</a>"></p>

<p>&hellip;we suddenly see the sun has totally arisen over the horizon and a new day is here.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/05/06/DJW.20160506.600D.0819.P1-HDR.jpg" width="800" height="500" title="&lsquo;sunrise from Mount Lofty House&rsquo; &lsquo;sunrise from Mount Lofty House&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/danijeljames/26776431501/sizes/l">https://www.flickr.com/photos/danijeljames/26776431501/sizes/l</a></p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/05/06/DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="&lsquo;DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1&rsquo; &lsquo;DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="/images/downloads/DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1.jpg">DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1</a> 12.6mb</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/05/06/DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="&lsquo;DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1&rsquo; &lsquo;DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="/images/downloads/DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1.jpg">DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1</a> 9.2mb</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[i will never stop fighting for love]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/03/i-will-never-stop-fighting-for-love/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-03T23:49:27+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/03/i-will-never-stop-fighting-for-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s not often that I will admit I make a mistake. I&rsquo;m a strong advocate for what I say being correct at the time and it should always continue to be correct because I said it. It&rsquo;s my belief. It&rsquo;s my virtue. It&rsquo;s my law.</p>

<p>A little while ago I met Jake. To be specific, I met him Saturday April 2<sup>nd</sup>. It was down in Semaphore under the clock tower <em>(now referred to as Jake &amp; Danijel&rsquo;s Clock Tower)</em>. Since that day my life has changed in a miraculous way that and I&rsquo;ve found the only man who has ever made time stand still every time I klep eyes on him. Without question, I have never understood the words <em>&ldquo;&hellip;fall in love in slow motion&rdquo;</em> until now.</p>

<p>One day since that time until now, Jake asked me a question. A simple question that I took not even more than a moment to reflex an answer from my values.</p>

<blockquote><p>Would you fight for me ?</p></blockquote>

<p>To go back in history, I&rsquo;d like to touch on a story about my great aunty and her husband. I don&rsquo;t recall the exact details but I&rsquo;d very much like to touch on this subject with her one day soon so I can capture the words myself and keep them safe to remind people that love like in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Notebook_(2004_film)">The Notebook</a> does exist in real life, and people can have it if you open your heart to it.</p>

<p>My great aunty was engaged to another man. Weeks before she was to be married, another man came by her and asked her for a date. She politely declined as she was already engaged to someone else. Not willing to take no for an answer, the man asked her the date. With a few weeks until she said &ldquo;I do&rdquo; with someone else he told her that he had that many weeks then to convince her that he was the better choice and she should marry him, because he felt more strongly for her.</p>

<p>I remember my mum quoting my great uncle saying something like:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t marry him, marry me. I&rsquo;m better than him. I&rsquo;ll love you better and you&rsquo;ll never be unhappy with me in your life. I&rsquo;ll show you the greatest love you can ever have.</p></blockquote>

<p>So what did he do ? He fought for her love. We live in a day and age when you can say there&rsquo;s not such thing as <em>&ldquo;love at first sight&rdquo;</em> but I tend to disagree strongly. He obviously felt like he was in love with her the moment he saw her and I can attest to the love they had lasted many years all through my youth and she loved him too until the day he died.</p>

<p>He fought. For her love. And he won. He fought every day for her love. And he won every day that he fought that battle. And my great aunty ne'er regret a single day by choosing the man who was my great uncle. I always admired their love. It was so strong and potent right to the last time they kissed each other goodnight for the endless sleep.</p>

<p>Before you wonder, yes - writing about this brings tears to my eyes. Tears of joy and happiness. I could write articles of the love between all the members of my family that I&rsquo;ve grown up with, including my parents. <em>(That&rsquo;s a story for another time !)</em></p>

<p>So then, you&rsquo;ll probably be wondering how did I answer Jake ? In the most notably ineffective way ever. Absolutely ever !</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been in a number of relationships that are both long and short, some that even spanned across states. And what did I learn from all these relationships from the past ? Something not great. I generated a reflex action that if someone wants to leave me; I let them go. But why you might ask ? Simple - I&rsquo;m here. They&rsquo;re there. They want to go, let them go. Celebrate what you had while it&rsquo;s there and enjoy it for the moment. Don&rsquo;t hold on to what you don&rsquo;t have.</p>

<p>👆 That there, is the worst advice I have ever given, to anyone or myself. Love is not expendable. If you can dispense with your love for someone; then they deserve to be with someone better - you never really truly loved them.</p>

<p>Once upon a time, a friend of mine who can see clearly to the core of who I am said to me:</p>

<blockquote><p>You are never truly in love with someone. You just accept them as the current person in your life.</p></blockquote>

<p>And you know what ? That person was correct. 100% correct. I never truly fell in love with anyone that was in my life. I generated a reflex action to a situation and added that to the core of my beliefs and behaviours. You could even refer to them as <em>&ldquo;The Laws of Danijel&rdquo;</em> which I live vehemently by, everyday of my life.</p>

<p>So without a moment&rsquo;s hesitation, I jerked into my usual reflex and answered his question in the most poor of methods. And it&rsquo;s stuck with me since then how I answered. Did I really believe what I was saying ? Why was it resounding in my memory ? Why was my dreams plagued with this question ? What was going on ?</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t believe it. Not one word. Nothing. It was all wrong. All of it !</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t let Jake walk out of my life. Not without a fight. Not at all. I&rsquo;m going to fight for him until my last breath. When I stop, it&rsquo;s because he&rsquo;s not reacting to me anymore and our love has died. I can&rsquo;t resuscitate something from the dead once it&rsquo;s gone for good.</p>

<p>Taking into consideration that I&rsquo;m going to fight, I need to elaborate why I&rsquo;m going to give it my all.</p>

<h3>Falling in love requires giving someone permission to break your heart.</h3>

<p>I have a special tattoo on my chest that is placed right over my heart. It&rsquo;s a Hōmonka (蜂紋華) which to me, represents <em>death in two steps</em>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/02/20160402.iPhone6Plus.133041.jpg" width="600" height="800" title="&lsquo;Hōmonka (蜂紋華)&rsquo; &lsquo;death in two steps&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The first step to the death of your heart <em>(love)</em> is the giving of your heart to someone. You don&rsquo;t have to give it whole, just a part of it. You sneak away into their soul and hide a small piece in the depths they never knew existed. There it stays forever. If there ever comes a time when the two of you walk away from each other, the second step is enacted and your heart&rsquo;s death will be sudden and the second step is complete.</p>

<p>I will never let Jake walk away with that piece of my heart in his soul without fighting for it. I&rsquo;ve given him permission to break my heart, but I don&rsquo;t want this to ever happen without giving it my all. For the first time ever in my life, I&rsquo;ve used my ninja skills to sneak into his soul and put a small piece of myself there that I don&rsquo;t want returned.</p>

<h3>The only love worth having is the love worth fighting for.</h3>

<p>There was a time not too long ago Jake had a bad day and said he was going to run away to Antartica. At that moment my heart stopped. It really hurt. I did a drawing with an arrow pointing to me and another with my representation of Antartica asking him if he chose me, or Antartica.</p>

<p>He chose me.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/05/20160405.iPhone5Plus.003021.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;antartica lost to me&rsquo; &lsquo;antartica lost to me&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t know what I would do next. If Jake hadn&rsquo;t chosen me, I quickly needed to find a way to prove to him I was the better choice. I wasn&rsquo;t going to give up that easily. Every single word in his response was going to touch me. I wanted to not let this go. Did I need to press rewind and go back to fix something ? Not this time. Not ever. I&rsquo;m not going to regret what I&rsquo;ve done, but I will make damned sure I do it right in the future.</p>

<p>The next image I sent him was me pointing my tongue at the penguin <em>(above)</em>, because I&rsquo;d won this round, and I was going to win every round from today until the day I kiss him my last goodnight.</p>

<h3>If I don&rsquo;t fight for it, I don&rsquo;t want it bad enough.</h3>

<p>Every single day I say good morning and I say goodnight. He&rsquo;s worth the blessings I give him. I want him to have a good day and a good night. It&rsquo;s not about what I can take from Jake, it&rsquo;s about what I can give Jake.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/05/04/20160504.jakes_goodnight.jpg" width="492" height="800" title="&lsquo;goodnight and sweet dreams jake&rsquo; &lsquo;goodnight and sweet dreams jake&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I want him. Every day. Every night. I want Jake in my life. I&rsquo;m going to show him this with every step of the way.</p>

<h3>If you love someone, let them go. If they return, they were always yours. If they don’t, they never were</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s not true.</p>

<p>Jake is the person that fills my heart with happiness and love. Doesn’t he deserve to be fought for ? Wouldn’t I want him to fight to keep me ? If he’s worth spending your life with, he’s worth fighting for!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/30/20160430.iPhone6Plus.112909.jpg" width="481" height="800" title="&lsquo;jake will be my husband one day&rsquo; &lsquo;jake will be my husband one day&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not over until I&rsquo;ve decided to let go. Just because Jake one day might say goodbye to me, it doesn&rsquo;t mean it&rsquo;s over. It just means I have even more of an incentive to fight for him. As long as I hold but don&rsquo;t keep fighting, it&rsquo;s not really love. As long as I still love him, I won&rsquo;t let the relationship be over, ever.</p>

<h3>If I wasn&rsquo;t willing to fight for it, then I&rsquo;m sorry&hellip;but Jake deserves better than me.</h3>

<p>And this is the truth that I will settle on. I was wrong. I&rsquo;m not going to let him go without making an effort. He&rsquo;s magical. I love all of him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sunrise from mt lofty house]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/26/sunrise-from-mt-lofty-house/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-26T11:16:54+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/26/sunrise-from-mt-lofty-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wasn&rsquo;t feeling well on the weekend and so my dear brought me dinner last night and a random visit which seemed to <em>bump</em> me back into life and get me happy and alive again. No longer do I look or feel like death reheated.</p>

<p>Not sure how to repay my dear, so I got up at 5:30 in the morning and went to Mt Lofty to see where I could find an amazing vantage point for the sunrise.</p>

<p>I discovered <a href="http://www.mtloftyhouse.com.au">Mount Lofty House</a>. I might have to plan a secret weekend getaway for the two of us up there sometime in the folding cold of winter and steal my dear away.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/26/20160426.iPhone6plus.0995.jpg" width="800" height="324" title="&lsquo;&rsquo; &lsquo;sunrise from Mt Lofty House on Tuesday&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Captured three images, this is the low-res version of one of them.</p>

<p>Good morning everyone !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my office window]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/19/my-office-window/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T13:21:22+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/19/my-office-window</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What does your office window view look like ? Do you even have an office window to look out ? I hope so. Everyone needs a window into the world. Especially our pets. Cats and dogs love being able to look into the world.</p>

<p>Did you ever look into the window as a child when it rained and watched the drops of rain falling from the heavens down on to the ground ? <em>plop, plop, plop</em> 💧💧💧 they would crash and splash like tiny meteors. I did. I also loved the sound.</p>

<p>Since moving to Adelaide I&rsquo;ve yet to find my office space that I will be working from. Hopefully it will have a nice view of the buildings, sky and all the people running around doing whatever they do best. Such a view would bring me joy.</p>

<p>When I worked for Vimeo, I had a view as grand as the Opera House, the Harbor Bridge, the people in Pitt St Mall, a coffee and cake, or even people walking by ! I technically had no office and worked entirely remotely from my office. That was in New York and here I was in Australia.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve managed to source my own office here in Adelaide whilst I work on personal projects and spread my wings a little and relax a little more. I&rsquo;m quite often here in my office but not during the usual business hours. They run 24/7. So you&rsquo;ll have to check my calendar <em>(sic.)</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/19/20160419.iPhone6Plus.0659.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;my office window&rsquo; &lsquo;my office window&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I hope your find a place to work, spending 1/3 of your adult life there, where the view is as beautiful as what I&rsquo;ve to share.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
