<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photography | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-04-20T01:53:00+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel James]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my office window]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/19/my-office-window/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-19T13:21:22+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/19/my-office-window</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What does your office window view look like ? Do you even have an office window to look out ? I hope so. Everyone needs a window into the world. Especially our pets. Cats and dogs love being able to look into the world.</p>

<p>Did you ever look into the window as a child when it rained and watched the drops of rain falling from the heavens down on to the ground ? <em>plop, plop, plop</em> 💧💧💧 they would crash and splash like tiny meteors. I did. I also loved the sound.</p>

<p>Since moving to Adelaide I&rsquo;ve yet to find my office space that I will be working from. Hopefully it will have a nice view of the buildings, sky and all the people running around doing whatever they do best. Such a view would bring me joy.</p>

<p>When I worked for Vimeo, I had a view as grand as the Opera House, the Harbor Bridge, the people in Pitt St Mall, a coffee and cake, or even people walking by ! I technically had no office and worked entirely remotely from my office. That was in New York and here I was in Australia.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve managed to source my own office here in Adelaide whilst I work on personal projects and spread my wings a little and relax a little more. I&rsquo;m quite often here in my office but not during the usual business hours. They run 24/7. So you&rsquo;ll have to check my calendar <em>(sic.)</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/19/20160419.iPhone6Plus.0659.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;my office window&rsquo; &lsquo;my office window&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I hope your find a place to work, spending 1/3 of your adult life there, where the view is as beautiful as what I&rsquo;ve to share.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[eba railway siding]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/10/eba-railway-siding/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-10T17:38:08+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/10/eba-railway-siding</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>A Little Bit of History</h4>

<p>The many settles of Eba built their own school in 1894, south of Eba. The walls of limestone are still upright and the limestone with 1894 etched in it was placed above the main door. It is weathering away and the etched numerals are hard to spot. The Lutheran settlers worshipped here (Section 246 in the Hundred of Eba). Later, a school was built next to the Albert Keough home, Section 188 in the Hundred of Eba, but this was not a satisfactory arrangement, so school was held in one of the empty settler&rsquo;s cottages.</p>

<p>Ebay Railway Siding has only the platform left as a reminder of busier days gone by. The 1984 school was build on Heppner land and is marked on old Morgan Council maps. Eba also boasted a Race Track; this was also on Heppner property. The track was laid around a small hill with the spectators on the mallee shaded hill, Section 201 in the Hundred of Eba. This gave the an unrestricted view of the races. The last Race Train from Kapunda to Eba ran in May of the year 1911.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/10/DJW.20160410.600D.0736.P1.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;luggage left on Eba Railway Siding&rsquo; &lsquo;luggage left on Eba Railway Siding&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/10/DJW.20160410.600D.0735.P1.jpg" width="533" height="800" title="&lsquo;smiley face badges in a jar&rsquo; &lsquo;smiley face badges in a jar&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/10/DJW.20160410.600D.0731.P1.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;passenger and dog waiting for last train&rsquo; &lsquo;passenger and dog waiting for last train&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[blue nights in adelaide]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/09/blue-nights-in-adelaide/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-09T22:50:26+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/09/blue-nights-in-adelaide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some random shots from my Sat night walking around Adelaide.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/09/DJW.20160409.600D.0721.P1.jpg" width="800" height="533" title="&lsquo;blue lights under bridge over River Torrens, Adelaide&rsquo; &lsquo;blue lights under bridge over River Torrens, Adelaide&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/09/DJW.20160409.600D.0725.P1.jpg" width="800" height="329" title="&lsquo;Adelaide Oval, Adelaide&rsquo; &lsquo;Adelaide Oval, Adelaide&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[breakfast for one]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/07/breakfast-for-one/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-07T00:13:48+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/07/breakfast-for-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gentlemen, may I warn you that when you live by yourself, this is what breakfast will look like if your parents don&rsquo;t teach you to cook for yourself, or you meet an honest husband/wife that you learn to make breakfast for them too. Why ? Because you love them !</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/04/04/20160404.iPhone6Plus.900142.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;toad in the hole&rsquo; &lsquo;bachelor toad in the hole breakfast&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[i want popsicles]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/03/29/i-want-popsicles/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-29T21:34:15+10:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/03/29/i-want-popsicles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want these popsicles to be recreated for a t-shirt print for my birthay&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/03/2016-summer-popsicles.jpg" width="600" height="600" title="&lsquo;summertime popsicles lyfe&rsquo; &lsquo;summertime popsicles lyfe&rsquo;" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
