<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: photography | danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-29T14:21:18+10:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel-James Wynyard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[smile 'cos someone loves you]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/04/smile-cos-someone-loves-you/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-04T12:31:39+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/08/04/smile-cos-someone-loves-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2016/08/04/IMG_4588.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="&lsquo;so much love&rsquo; &lsquo;so much love&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[303 by the seas]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/31/303-by-the-sea/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-31T12:07:18+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/31/303-by-the-sea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, scrolling through Yelp! looking for a new place to go eat at and came across the venue <a href="https://www.yelp.com.au/biz/303-by-the-sea-henley-beach">303 By The Sea</a>. We&rsquo;ve been there already but had to sit outside because of my indecisiveness. So now we&rsquo;re back and we got a nice table at the back of the room.</p>

<p>The lines are long, it&rsquo;s loud, people are sighing, you&rsquo;re really waiting a while to get served - but who can question the quality of the food being served!? It looks amazing.</p>

<p>Jake wanted a hashbrown, eggs, mushrooms and bacon - just simple. Well, apparently not. After discovering the hashbrowns are a meal unto themselves and can&rsquo;t be served with the condiments I asked for, the chef came over and disagreed with my request. As I asked her, I don&rsquo;t mind how much this is going to cost me - find a suitable price and let me have what I want.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/31/IMG_4497.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;waiting impatiently&rsquo; &lsquo;waiting impatiently&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>It took them a while to get his food out to us. I really was quite impressed with the quality of my food, but I can&rsquo;t really rave about the experience as a whole. We took to Facebook to make comments about the quality of the experience and endured a tirade from the Madam Chef on Facebook. Sheesh! I don&rsquo;t know what the problem was. Maybe she was having a bad day?</p>

<p>All in all, it&rsquo;s a great place, but I think it&rsquo;ll be some time before we come back here. Maybe in the summertime instead?</p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[food, football, fun]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/07/food-football-fun/"/>
    <updated>2016-07-07T11:35:04+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/07/07/food-football-fun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So who would have ever thought that I&rsquo;d be intersted in sport? Not me, that&rsquo;s for sure. It&rsquo;s Friday and Jake&rsquo;s organised something for us to do. What exactly I&rsquo;m not sure. But why would I care? As long as I&rsquo;m spending time with him I just know that my life is the greatest achievement.</p>

<p>We ended up first at a restaurant on North Tce that I hadn&rsquo;t been to, but eyeing off since I got back to Adelaide. Argentinian influenced steak house/tapas bar. Service was a bit below par, but the waitress lightened up the mood. Food was incredibly juicy and I really liked it.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.yelp.com.au/biz/la-boca-bar-and-grill-adelaide">La Boca</a> is generally pretty busy from what I&rsquo;ve observed each time I&rsquo;ve been past so it was great to finally get in here and have a look at the place.</p>

<p>Heading down to the football we grabbed a drink each and went down to our favourite spot. It&rsquo;s not the first time I&rsquo;ve come to the football with Jake and I feel like he&rsquo;s opened my eyes to appreciate the simpler things in life I&rsquo;ve learned to reject. Maybe I should pick a team and get a season pass for the two of us? That would make a nice surprise and we&rsquo;ll finally start to accumulate elements in our life which belong to nobody else but ourselves.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/07/IMG_3770.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;standing on the hill&rsquo; &lsquo;standing on the hill&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After the football match we went down to the carpark to find some Pokémon to build up our Pokédex more. Bored with this we went on to the Alpine Winter Village on North Tce. What do we see apart from crap food and llamas? Ice arena! Fuck yes!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/07/IMG_3798.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;boys on the ice&rsquo; &lsquo;boys on the ice&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Poor Jake fell over totally whilst I was busy filming a selfie video. He fell just out of the frame and I had tears literally flowing freely as I keeled over to laugh instead of going over to help him. What kind of a boyfriend am I? The worst kind!</p>

<p>Before the night was over we stopped in at a little photo booth van to get 4 black and white selfies - the old style selfie - in a film strip. I love this photo so much of us. I&rsquo;ve never had a chance to do something cool and fun like this all my life and secretly always been jealous of the people that keep images like this in their wallet. Thank you Jake. This was an amazing night. You&rsquo;re the greatest.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/07/07/IMG_3979.jpg" width="600" height="800" title="&lsquo;photo booth fun&rsquo; &lsquo;photo booth fun&rsquo;" ></p>

<p><code>#TheLostArchives</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[jake take me home]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/26/jake-take-me-home/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-26T23:01:58+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/26/jake-take-me-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How did the day start? Perfect. I went to get Jake to start the day. 😍</p>

<p>First we went to the HMAS Adelaide Open Day.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/26/DJW.20160626.iPhone6SPlus.3303.800res.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;HMAS Adelaide&rsquo; &lsquo;HMAS Adelaide&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Afterwards Jake and I were supposed to go on the Dolphin Cruise <em>(he&rsquo;s so sneaky, he organised this without telling me!)</em> but we missed that because the tour of the ship took longer than it was supposed to. How did I ever deserve this man? What did I do? I don&rsquo;t know. All I know, is this is the perfect life.</p>

<p>We thought about it, and I suggested Hahndorf. On the way, we went to a winery to do a cheese and wine testing. I&rsquo;ve never done this before! So why not?</p>

<p>Jake brought me to Shaw &amp; Smith cellar door where we took a flight. A wine flight! Did you know that? Tell me I&rsquo;m not the only silly person who doesn&rsquo;t know these things? A wine flight!? Ha! What a cute name. So we took a trip together.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/26/DJW.20160626.iPhone6SPlus.3347.800res.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;Wine Flight&rsquo; &lsquo;Wine Flight&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>After this wonderful matching we headed into Hahndorf, stopped at a market, then across the road to the candy shop and then back here.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/26/DJW.20160626.iPhone6SPlus.3355.800res.jpg" width="800" height="600" title="&lsquo;I want all the candy&rsquo; &lsquo;I want all the candy&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Unfortunately after dinner I had to bring Jake home. He wasn&rsquo;t feeling well and wouldn&rsquo;t have been able to sleep at my place because the bed is quite hard. 😔</p>

<blockquote><p>Jake, take me home&hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p>That&rsquo;s right, I can hardly hold back my anticipation. There is going to be a day in the future, when I can fall over drunk and turn to this man, and say to him, <em>&ldquo;Jake, take me home&rdquo;</em> and we&rsquo;ll be going back to the same place that we both share together. Our house. Our home. And we&rsquo;ll have a cute dog.</p>

<p>Hopefully the lady next door won&rsquo;t grow ugly tulips so I don&rsquo;t have to complain! 😂</p>

<blockquote><p>11:11, make a wish&hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s just passed 11:11 as I&rsquo;m writing this, so make a wish. ✨</p>

<p>My wish, is simple. For Jake &amp; Danijel <code>#jakeanddanijel</code> to enjoy a long and wonderful life full of laughter, smiles and wonderful memories.</p>

<p>Goodnight!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[spicy chiken chipotle white pumpkin fettuccini]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/20/spicy-chiken-chipotle-white-pumpkin-fettuccini/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-20T19:59:29+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/20/spicy-chiken-chipotle-white-pumpkin-fettuccini</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever had the idea to fusion two dishes together and hope it go well? I did. And it worked! 🙌🏻</p>

<p>Taking the idea of carbonara being a white-sauced bacon dish and pumpkin fetta pasta, I thought to myself, why can&rsquo;t I make this into two new dishes? It can&rsquo;t be that hard, can it?</p>

<p>First things first, Jake likes spicy food. Not spicy enough to burn a new hole in your arse, but something nice. 🌶🌶🌶😋 Why not try to make the base of both these dishes into something new and use some of my chipotle sauce to bring it together? It&rsquo;s worth a shot! 🔫</p>

<p>Pumpkin in a pasta dish need to be firm, so I took some kent and butternut pumpkins and roasted them with olive oil, thyme, cracked pepper and salt crystals and ground salt for ~45mins @ 180°C <em>(fan forced)</em> and then left them in there until I was ready. I did turn them about half way through to make sure they baked evenly.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/20/DJW.20160620.iPhone6SPlus.3126.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;roast pumpkin cubes&rsquo; &lsquo;roast pumpkin cubes&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>On to the main dish. Starting with onion, I sweated it until it became translucent and added chilli then chicken and a glob of my chipotle sauce. It needed to mix around and get juicy on a low temperature to bind the flavours. Added some more salt.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/20/DJW.20160620.iPhone6SPlus.3125.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;create the chicken base&rsquo; &lsquo;create the chicken base&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Why all the salt? Well, saw this crazy Korean woman <em>(Maangchi)</em> on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/?gl=AU&amp;hl=en-GB">YouTube</a> when she started with a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4zNKal3PI_Q">Korean style iced coffee - Naeng-keopi: 냉커피</a> and then followed her around and saw lots of videos that use salt - a lot of salt! I&rsquo;m surprised she didn&rsquo;t put salt in her iced coffee! 😂</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/20/20160620.Maangchi.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;Maangchi&rsquo; &lsquo;Maanghi&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Anyway, back to the dish at hand. 😁</p>

<p>So then you skin and chop up some mushrooms, fry for a bit on low heat, add chopped bacon, fry some more, add &frac12; cup of white wine <em>(something cheap will do)</em>, add &frac12; cup of chicken or vegetable stock, bring to the boil and simmer for 10 mins. Add the chicken stuff to this, including all the juices and add about &frac12; cup of cream and simmer for 10 mins.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/20/DJW.20160620.iPhone6SPlus.3137.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;sauce is ready&rsquo; &lsquo;sauce is ready&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>Right before serving, add the pumpkin we made earlier and some baby spinach and stir until the spinach is wilted. Get your pasta ready and put it on the bowls, scoop some sauce on top and serve!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/20/DJW.20160620.iPhone6SPlus.3140.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;perfect dish&rsquo; &lsquo;perfect dish&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I get called a <code>#masterchef</code> by Jake all the time. Half of me believes because he loves me so much, the other half because of the taste I procure to his palate!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016/06/20/DJW.20160620.iPhone6SPlus.3144.800res.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="&lsquo;bowls are clean&rsquo; &lsquo;bowls are clean&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>A clean bowl is a perfect dish ✌️</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
