<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[danijelj [p.f.h]]]></title>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://danijelj.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-08T22:18:55+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://danijelj.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Danijel-James Wynyard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[soufflé round 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/08/souffle-round-2/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-08T16:22:36+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/08/souffle-round-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got home from a night at Jake&rsquo;s <em>(awww&hellip;.😍😘😍)</em> and Tom was eagerly awaiting me to make soufflé for him.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/08/20160608.iPhone6SPlus.2539.800.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="doing what i do best, whipping" alt="doing what i do best, whipping"></p>

<p>The results ? Of course they&rsquo;re a success ! Jake called me a <a href="https://tenplay.com.au/channel-ten/masterchef">MasterChef</a> 😉</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/08/20160608.iPhone6SPlus.2537.800.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="MasterChef Danijel beats with love" alt="MasterChef Danijel beats with love"></p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to make food for Jake for the rest of his life. I think my experience with the kitchen and food is enough to bring to our relationship that something that will last our lifetime spent together. I do hope he knows how much I love him. He&rsquo;s the sunshine on a rainy day for me.</p>

<p>Did Tom like the soufflé, naturally of course. Whipped cream and all !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[breakfast is served]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/07/breakfast-is-served/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-07T11:39:02+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/07/breakfast-is-served</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Who wants breakfast at the Haus of Danni-Jel ? You do, bitches :P</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/07/20160607.iPhobne6SPlus.2427.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="breakfast deluxe" alt="breakfast deluxe"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[you know your awesome when]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/04/you-know-your-awesome-when/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-04T21:29:27+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/04/you-know-your-awesome-when</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Logged into <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a> today and noticed that some of my commits have been rolled into a globally used Bootstrap theme ! So much fun !</p>

<p><img src="images/2016/06/04/20160504.git-pulls-used.png" width="800" height="176" title="git pulls added" alt="git pulls added"></p>

<p>Fuck yeah !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello paddy's lantern]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/02/hello-paddys-lantern/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-02T10:42:32+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/02/hello-paddys-lantern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Arriving back here in Adelaide on March 3rd this year, one of the first things I did was take to social platform <a href="http://www.grindr.com">Grindr</a> to get a feel from everyone where the best coffee shops were. Yesterday I was talking to Jakey and asked him if he&rsquo;s ever heard of <a href="http://paddyslantern.com.au">Paddy&rsquo;s Lantern</a>. Unfortunately not, and I did leave it to the last two of places to still check out.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t remember who referred me this venue, but thank you, whoever you are ! It was an absolute delight !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/02/1438068476190.png" width="800" height="500" title="paddys lantern" alt="paddys lantern"></p>

<p>Nested in the suburban district of Adelaide hidden amongst the old houses at 219 Gilbert Street, this little niche cafe can be found.</p>

<p>The food was amazing, coffee was amazing and to top it off - the service was brilliant !</p>

<p>I picked myself the <em>2 Fried Eggs w/ Spicy Relish on Sourdough Toast</em> and at only $13 this was a total bargain ! You can&rsquo;t go wrong with the perfectly cooked eggs, rustic sourdough, and devilish homemade spicy relish. Mmmmm !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/02/20160602.iPhone6SPlus.091706.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="Eggs, Spicy Relish, Sourdough" alt="Eggs, Spicy Relish, Sourdough"></p>

<p>I also got my standard large size soy latte, no sugar as this is what I really came for. Keeping up standards, I had it served in a takeaway cup. I was a little taken back by the service of being offered my cup still on a saucer, and not just handed to me.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/02/20160602.iPhone6SPlus.091446.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="soy latte takeaway" alt="soy latte takeaway"></p>

<p>The print on the cups is faded, but even so it&rsquo;s still so cute ! 😊 I can&rsquo;t delay my observations of a full bodied flavour with amazing texture steamed perfectly and no burning with a lasting aroma - wow ! This has to be <em>the</em> coffee in Adelaide. They deserve the 4&frac12; stars awarded to them on <a href="http://www.yelp.com.au/biz/paddys-lantern-adelaide">Yelp!</a> too !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/02/20160602.iPhone6SPlus.093056.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="second coffee to go thnx" alt="second coffee to go thnx"></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re in the area and you want amazing breakfast, please head on down there, bring your partner, work colleagues or a friend and enjoy the simplicity of the atmosphere, the warmth of the service, the spectacular tastes of the products and most importantly - experience it for yourself !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[car wash and lamb dinner]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/01/car-wash-and-lamb-dinner/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-01T10:40:35+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/06/01/car-wash-and-lamb-dinner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh no, what&rsquo;s he done ? Jake&rsquo;s given me his car for the day !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.095132.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="uh oh spaghetti-o" alt="uh oh spaghetti-o"></p>

<p>This poor man is always tired, stressed or sleeping. What do you think I&rsquo;m gonna do today ? That&rsquo;s easy. I&rsquo;m gonna wash his car for him and surprise him at the end of the day 😄</p>

<p>I went to the RepCo or whatever it&rsquo;s called near my house and got some supplies. When I was young I had a weekend job that saw me travelling to car yards each Saturday morning and I&rsquo;d wash the cars. It wasn&rsquo;t how many cars were washed per hour, it was here&rsquo;s $150, go was as many cars as you can per hour for 3 hours. Not bad when you&rsquo;re 14 !</p>

<p>Men like pink, right ? Well, I&rsquo;m a man and I&rsquo;m not afraid of pink, and I love the bubblegum smell of the detergent I picked for this job too!</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.110357.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="sweet like bubblegum" alt="sweet like bubblegum"></p>

<p>So how do I go with this job ? Fantastic darling, absolutely fantastic. I remember Jake saying to me that the one time he goes to wash his car, and so does the whole of Adelaide. LOL This is going to be perfect opportunity for me to do something for him, and him alone. It&rsquo;s not a present. It&rsquo;s not something I&rsquo;ve made. It&rsquo;s something I can do for the sake of doing it for him because this is what real love is about. It&rsquo;s what you can do for that person to make their life a little better. Call it a miracle, if you will, I try to perform a miracle each day for Jake. That&rsquo;s always on my agenda.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.113541.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="wash wash wash" alt="wash wash wash"></p>

<p>To say that washing his car was worth it would be an understatement. It saved Jake so much time and effort; and now it&rsquo;s one less thing that he can worry about.</p>

<p>But he&rsquo;s coming over for dinner tonight, <em>yeah, it&rsquo;s not like we&rsquo;re never getting married or anything, so may as well show him that I can cook, and well sic.,</em> so what do I make him ? I know&hellip;his favourite dish - Lamb ! Best part is, I&rsquo;ve not cooked lamb for anyone &hellip; EVER !</p>

<p>Obviously it was good when you see someone staring on at their food wanting do devour it, &lsquo;eh ?</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.2160.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="can i have my lamb now?" alt="can i have my lamb now?"></p>

<p>I think our collaborative effort to make dinner, <em>Jake made the veggies, I made the sauce just for his palate and the lamb to my own style,</em> and it came out pretty swish if you ask me !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.2170.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="a dish well made" alt="a dish well made"></p>

<p>Would you say that was a great dinner Jake ? Oh what&rsquo;s that ? 10/10 ? Lee Lin Chin would be proud ! 5 Stars !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/06/01/20160601.iPhone6SPlus.202632.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="i love this man" alt="i love this man"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[roast chicken for dinner]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/31/roast-chicken-for-dinner/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-31T21:22:11+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/31/roast-chicken-for-dinner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight we had lemon, garlic and herb roast chicken with middle bacon to cover served with roast potato and carrot !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/31/20160531.iPhone6SPlus.2063.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="roast chicken" alt="roast chicken"></p>

<p>Apparently we&rsquo;re recovering from the weekend, but why not have a glass of red, just &lsquo;cos ?</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/31/20160531.iPhone6SPlus.2070.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="one glass" alt="one glass"></p>

<p>Spun up some souflée realness using Nutella too !</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/31/20160531.iPhone6SPlus.2077.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="nutella realness" alt="nutella realness"></p>

<p>Do you think this was a good mean Jake ? 8.5/10 ! Sweet as ! <em>The potatoes were a little hard :(</em></p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/31/20160531.iPhone6SPlus.203826.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="jake & danijel" alt="jake & danijel"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[breakfast with jakey]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/28/breakfast-with-jakey/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-28T00:11:09+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/28/breakfast-with-jakey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jake brought me out for breakfast this morning. We went to the cafe that sits behind the playground he talks so often and fondly of.</p>

<p>He bought me french toast. Yummy ! 😋🇫🇷🍞</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/28/20160528.french_toast_with_jakey.jpg" width="800" height="800"  alt="french toast"></p>

<p>He got a yucky toasted cheese &amp; ham sandwich &lsquo;cos they don&rsquo;t have bacon 😂</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Type Symbols for Option]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/21/how-to-type-symbols-for-option/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-21T11:41:07+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/21/how-to-type-symbols-for-option</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are the Unicode hex numbers for the most common symbols used to represent Mac control keys. You can type these by finding the numbers in the Character Palette or similar font inspector program, or by using the Unicode Hex Keyboard (key in Option plus the number). Lucida Grande is a good font to use.</p>

<p>Apple/Command: 2318 ⌘</p>

<p>Alt/Option: 2325 ⌥</p>

<p>Shift: 21E7 ⇧</p>

<p>Delete: 232B ⌫</p>

<p>Control: 2303 ⌃</p>

<p>Apple Logo: F8FF or Option-Shift-K </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How lucky am I to have something that makes saying goodbye so hard.]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/18/how-lucky-am-i-to-have-something-that-makes-saying-goodbye-so-hard/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-18T01:38:09+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/18/how-lucky-am-i-to-have-something-that-makes-saying-goodbye-so-hard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a while someone will come through your life and the whole game will change.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been lucky enough in my life that I&rsquo;ve always been the one to walk away and not regret the choice to do so. I&rsquo;m not a cold-hearted person or without any emotions, rather they&rsquo;re difficult to be interpreted by other people and it&rsquo;s without regret that I&rsquo;ve not come across someone that&rsquo;s going to make me bring these to the surface.</p>

<p>Recently I wrote about someone special that came into my life but I haven&rsquo;t been able to get the whole story down pat and I think it&rsquo;s time I put these memories into words so I don&rsquo;t forget who they were, even if I don&rsquo;t see them again. 😔</p>

<p>Before I left Sydney, I spoke a colleague of mine <em>(from a different department)</em> named Gillian who told me I need to start writing my memories down and keeping them so that one day I can look back on it all and reflect. It&rsquo;s funny that I was only thinking of Gillian the other day when she wrote to me via email today to enquire how I was. Thank you Gillian 😊 I haven&rsquo;t forgotten you and I have thought about you a few times since leaving Sydney. I&rsquo;m glad you&rsquo;re doing well ✌️</p>

<p>So back to my story - <em>I get easily side-tracked</em> - we met and we went from there. First meeting under the <a href="https://c8.staticflickr.com/4/3633/3366493095_d2d02753ed_b.jpg">Semaphore Clock Tower</a> we went for a walk down the jetty and then along the foreshore and eventually landed ourselves a table at a local cafe. From there we went to <a href="http://www.kmart.com.au">K-Mart</a> and picked out some bedsheets for him and then back to each other&rsquo;s respective home.</p>

<p>I saw him again, and again, and again ! What was it that drew me to this person above anyone else that I&rsquo;ve met in my life ? Something twinged inside me and for a long time I&rsquo;ve never been able to put my thumb on it. All I knew was this was good, and I was happy. I started to open up emotionally and discovered that I could evolve in ways I didn&rsquo;t know existed within the parameters of my soul.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spoken many times in my life about the three aspects that make you human. They are your body, your mind, and your soul. But what about the heart ? Do I try to confuse everyone by saying the soul is the heart ? No. Never. The heart is the fourth aspect of being human, and this is created when two people meet for the first time.</p>

<p>How so, I hear you ask ? Well, let me explain.</p>

<p>The heart is created the first time two people come together. It&rsquo;s an emotional connection. When you care about someone, the distance between the two of you is the stretch of that connection and that&rsquo;s where the heart is physically born. If you lived on this earth as the only person in existence you would never know the aspect of the heart as it cannot be created by yourself. It&rsquo;s shared from the components the two of you put into the middle.</p>

<p>If you believe with all your heart that you belong with that person, then you will reside there for an eternity of time and I don&rsquo;t care what anyone says, they&rsquo;ll never forget you. Even after the last goodbye.</p>

<blockquote><p>Promise you won’t forget me, ever. Not even when I’m a hundred.</p></blockquote>

<p>I won&rsquo;t even need to ask this person to not forget me if I&rsquo;ve created the heart with them. Not even when I&rsquo;m a hundred, because I&rsquo;ll be with them forever. I entrust my heart to this person and know that even if I die alone I will not be forgotten as the memories will carry on with them. ☺️</p>

<p>So as time goes on, we start to tread waters and I&rsquo;m finding myself falling in the best possible way - without boundaries. Soon before long I found myself thinking about them every day and occupying a major percentage of where this amazing ecstacy in my life comes from.</p>

<p>Though there wouldn&rsquo;t be a story if there wasn&rsquo;t at least one broken heart, a moment of silence and a phoenix to rise from the fire.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/18/20160518.lucky_to_say_goodbye.jpg" width="533" height="800" title="something that makes saying goodbye so hard" alt="something that makes saying goodbye so hard"></p>

<p>Have you ever felt that it was hard to say goodbye ? Have you ever been so lucky ?</p>

<p>I remember the last time I saw my grandfather in hospital and knew this would be the last time I ever got to see him alive. Did I feel sad ? No. Not really. Call me cold-hearted. I don&rsquo;t care. It&rsquo;s a fact.</p>

<p>I celebrated my love for him as my mentor when growing up and showing me the endurance of love through the years that I had with him. See, the situation is a little more tangled that I let you know. So I&rsquo;ll explain. My grandmother had a memory problem and creating short-term and keeping long-term memories was a problem. My memories of my grandparents has always been my grandfather staying close to her, reminding her where she is, and what she&rsquo;s doing. He kept a close eye on her so she didn&rsquo;t get lost and always was safe and sound. It sounds like he was controlling, but not really. He refused to put her in a nursing home. That was his wife who he&rsquo;d spent all those years of marriage with and he wanted to keep her close to him now in the time of her need. Can anyone else say they&rsquo;ve seen this kind of dedication ? I hope so !</p>

<p>After my grandmother passed away I kind of remember a shift in my grandfather&rsquo;s emotions, he let go. That was his life that had passed away from his hands. Sure, he had three daughters, one of which is <a href="https://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/happy-mothers-day/">my mother</a> but at some point his heart broke. The only part of his heart that still existed was the memories he shared and created with the heart that was born between the two of them. They&rsquo;re names are Denise and Thelma. I share part of my name with my grandfather. The James component. So regardless of whether I had a heart with him or not, I share something with him eternally. 😁</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t have to say goodbye to my grandfather, or my grandmother. They live eternally with me in my memories. I never let them go, they stay with me every day.</p>

<p>In a <a href="https://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/03/i-will-never-stop-fighting-for-love/">previous post</a>, I mentioned that a friend said to me that I&rsquo;m never truly in love with someone and I agree. But that was before I met this person. I could say their name, but at this point in time I need to let them settle on how things have come about and I need to take this time to reflect too.</p>

<p>We didn&rsquo;t do anything wrong. Not at all. It&rsquo;s just that we&rsquo;ve got to take some time to evaluate the situation at hand.</p>

<p>Myself, I am an emotionally strong person. I&rsquo;ve spent years and years learning how to connect with my emotions and trying to understand them better. I&rsquo;m an Aries. And yes I do believe firmly in the science of astrology. It&rsquo;s not verbatim, I can&rsquo;t prove this is right or wrong. Just accept it, that&rsquo;s all.</p>

<p>In the past you could say I was a violent person. I would lash out and let my emotions rule and control my behaviour without much room for a buffer. Then I said something to someone one day in a fit of anger and the feeling that came over me after letting those words go showed me that you truly can stab someone <em>(no pun intended)</em> with just words and words alone. I had literally put a knife deep into their soul and cut them. Was I sorry for what I said ? No. And I&rsquo;m still not. I don&rsquo;t like her. She&rsquo;s a bitch. What I took away from that was that it&rsquo;s now time to sit back, see what I&rsquo;m doing, what I&rsquo;ve done, and look to where I want to be. So, I now control my anger. I don&rsquo;t lash out with horrible words or go break plates or drive my car through shop windows - yes that&rsquo;s a true story and I&rsquo;ll write about it one day too.</p>

<p>For many years I&rsquo;ve had the pent up emotion inside of me that&rsquo;s been yearning to find a way to express. That emotion can ignite the hearts of stars across the night sky. Fuse rubies in the hearts of planets. Dry entire oceans across the lands. Drench the forests in torrents of waters. There is no limit to this emotion.</p>

<p>It found an outlet. The very person that I&rsquo;ve been talking about this whole time.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s the single most truest emotion of all my repository of emotions and it comes without end to expression once we travel it&rsquo;s road.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I haven&rsquo;t been able to control this emotion. It comes out so naturally, and because it does this and being so strong, it&rsquo;s like a tidal force against a single flower a world with an unchanging night sky, an endless white desert across the ground. Nothing exists here except this lone flower.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/18/20160518.endlesswhitesands.png" width="800" height="565" title="endless white sands" alt="endless white sands"></p>

<blockquote><p>I didn&rsquo;t pull back, I was so enraptured. This is my downfall.</p></blockquote>

<p>My downfall was that I didn&rsquo;t heed the notice given to me and pull back a little bit. This lone flower stands by itself in the endless desert and it sees no stars or sun. Just an unchanging foreverness. It&rsquo;s always been like this.</p>

<p>So now the flower has suffocated under the tsunami of emotions and I&rsquo;m left in a place where I can only sit back to contemplate.</p>

<p>After a reflection on the words said to me tonight, I&rsquo;ve come to the conclusion of two things.</p>

<p>The first being that this person might be scared of love and never experienced it properly before and they don&rsquo;t know what to do with these feelings. I should have recognised this and let them time to process this and take it slowly and thoughtfully. Yes, I&rsquo;m well established in my principles and behaviours. I don&rsquo;t like to admit this, but I&rsquo;m really not perfect. I&rsquo;d like you to believe I was and write whole books on how to be a respectable person.</p>

<blockquote><p>But who am I to instruct you ? I&rsquo;m not !</p></blockquote>

<p>The second being this person seems to think the <em>ONLY</em> reason I stay in Adelaide is because of them and I hate it here.</p>

<p>I take these two main instruments and carve them into two lessons for myself.</p>

<h3>The First Lesson</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to think I&rsquo;ve reached the peak of my evolution. But didn&rsquo;t I say that to myself when I was 23 too ? Didn&rsquo;t I stand there in front of a whole group of people saying something stupid like <em>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s nothing left for me to learn in this world. I&rsquo;ve learned all there is to know.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Fucking hell I was a stupid young man. Who ever said there&rsquo;s nothing left to learn ? Well, obviously me. Even just tonight I said something just as selfish and stupid.</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ve reached the peak of my evolution, and there&rsquo;s nothing left to aspire to.</p></blockquote>

<p>FUCK ! NO !</p>

<p>No on so many levels. Just no. Why ? Because I said that just at the beginning of this year and then what ? Well, along came this person, and I learned something totally new. Emotions. Ways of being. Personality traits. Behaviours. Laughter. Sadness. Anticipation. So many things I can&rsquo;t even being to process them all.</p>

<h3>The Second Lesson</h3>

<p>Referring to an email I send to Gillian earlier today whilst waiting out the front of his work to finish, I&rsquo;ll pull the most quintessential quote out into the open&hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p>&hellip;then I remember that this is my home&hellip;</p></blockquote>

<p>That&rsquo;s right. Adelaide is my home. I got off that plane and I made a decision to live here and make my life. I think I&rsquo;ve been so bored without work that I&rsquo;m going crazy in my own mind a little bit and need something to focus on. Because of that I&rsquo;ve said some really stupid thoughts which have been stirring around in my mind. I&rsquo;ve been hating on Adelaide and that has created an unnecessary pressure on this person and can it be possible that they now feel like I&rsquo;m only here because of them and I want to leave ?</p>

<blockquote><p>&hellip;I&rsquo;ve been so caught up being emotionally moved by him that I forgot to expose him to my other temperaments.</p></blockquote>

<p>I forgot to show him where my true love lies in Adelaide. The rhythm and the beat of the people. Who knew me in Sydney ? Did you ? Maybe you did and maybe you didn&rsquo;t. What was that one thing I always said I loved about Australia ? It was Adelaide and her people.</p>

<p>This person deserved to see my other temperaments and unfortunately I didn&rsquo;t reign back on the prime emotion and look where it&rsquo;s led us now.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t know how many times I heard or read the words <em>&ldquo;you scare me&rdquo;</em>. Why was I created so scientifically intelligent that I&rsquo;m so readily and easily able to overlook the most simple things in life - what is right before me. I&rsquo;m always in the dark.</p>

<p>So now, we&rsquo;re at a point where I&rsquo;ve listened, learned, and will continue to learn. I&rsquo;ve said my true representation of what I want. I want them to come back.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s never been a time that I was scared until now. Only a few words ushered have given me a whole new perspective. They&rsquo;re going to be quiet for a while. That&rsquo;s OK. I can deal with that. I want them to take what they need from this. It&rsquo;s the part that followed that scared me. 💀</p>

<blockquote><p>I may not come back fyi</p></blockquote>

<p>Right now I&rsquo;ve come to a point with this person where I know there is a possibility that maybe they might not come back, and all I can say is this:</p>

<blockquote><p>How lucky I am to have something that makes saying goodbye so hard.</p></blockquote>

<p>So, did I start this article with the right words ? Clearly not. Let me try that again.</p>

<blockquote><p>I&rsquo;ve been UNLUCKY enough in my life that I&rsquo;ve always been the one to walk away and not regret the choice to do so.</p></blockquote>

<h3>A Final Note</h3>

<p>There&rsquo;s a <a href="http://banksy.co.uk">Banksy</a> image referred to as <em>&ldquo;Girl With Balloon&rdquo;</em> that represents letting go of what makes you sad. I&rsquo;m not sure I agree with this sentiment.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/18/20160518.banksy-girl-with-balloon.jpg" width="600" height="675" title="never give up" alt="never give up"></p>

<p>To me this image is a sole representation of never giving up. The little girl represents me and the balloon him. I&rsquo;m reaching out, but I&rsquo;m not gonna run yet. The balloon will hover there and when it&rsquo;s ready it will go whichever way it wants. If it floats back towards me, I&rsquo;m going to hold it by the thread between my fingers and slowly hold the thread with more fingers the closer the balloon is ready to come. If ever. 😊</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[happy mothers day]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/happy-mothers-day/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-08T10:42:21+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/happy-mothers-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To the strongest woman I&rsquo;ve ever known. Raising three boys, all ratbags 😁 Our mother, is the bone of our spines, keeping us straight and true. She is our blood, making sure it runs rich and strong. She is the beating of our hearts. I cannot imagine a life without her. To the world you are a mother, to your three ratbags you are our world. Happy Mothers Day Mum 😘💐🌟</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/08/14910844667_bae4756d72_c.jpg" width="629" height="800" title="my mother" alt="my mother"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[convert mp4 to webm with ffmpeg]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/convert-mp4-to-webm-with-ffmpeg/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-08T01:09:08+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/08/convert-mp4-to-webm-with-ffmpeg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Convert from MP4 to WebM standard:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>avconv -i inputVideo.mp4 -acodec libvorbis -aq <span class="m">5</span> -ac <span class="m">2</span> -qmax <span class="m">25</span> -threads <span class="m">2</span> outputVideo.webm
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[quick brew install tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/07/quick-brew-install-tips/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-07T23:42:06+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/07/quick-brew-install-tips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes I need to remind myself how to install a list of apps in <a href="http://brew.sh">brew</a> from a textfile named <code>file.txt</code></p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>sed -i <span class="s1">&#39;/^\s*$/d&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># in place remove blank lines</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>cat file.txt <span class="p">|</span> <span class="k">while</span> <span class="nb">read </span>in<span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">do</span> brew install <span class="s2">&quot;$in&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">done</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># read each line in &#39;file.txt&#39; to brew to install</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>xargs -0 brew install  &lt; &lt;<span class="o">(</span>tr <span class="se">\\</span>n <span class="se">\\</span><span class="m">0</span> &lt;file.txt<span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c"># brew install each line from file.txt</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[getting an awesome wallpaper]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/06/getting-an-awesome-wallpaper/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-06T03:34:52+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/06/getting-an-awesome-wallpaper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having made a promise that I would go back and get a photograph of the sunrise to make a wallpaper for the <a href="http://www.apple.com/au/shop/buy-iphone/iphone6s">iPhone 6S Plus</a>, I finally got back up to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Lofty">Mount Lofty</a> this morning and managed to capture some interesting shots.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I didn&rsquo;t think to bring my other lenses with me when I came up here so I was limited to my <a href="https://www.canon.com.au/en-AU/Personal/Support-Help/Product-Help/Camera-Accessories/Camera-Lenses/EF-S%2018-55mm%20f35-56%20IS%20II">18-55mm</a> lens, but managed to capture some nice shots.</p>

<p>The sun comes up pretty quickly too ! Honestly, it&rsquo;s not there one moment, then suddenly she&rsquo;s peeping her head over the horizon and then&hellip;</p>

<p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/7offL3yehzrKU/giphy.gif"></p>

<p>&hellip;we suddenly see the sun has totally arisen over the horizon and a new day is here.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/06/DJW.20160506.600D.0819.P1-HDR.jpg" width="800" height="500" title="sunrise from Mount Lofty House" alt="sunrise from Mount Lofty House"></p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/danijeljames/26776431501/sizes/l">https://www.flickr.com/photos/danijeljames/26776431501/sizes/l</a></p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/06/DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1" alt="DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1"></p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="http://danijelj.com/images/downloads/DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1.jpg">DJW.20160506.600D.0750.P1</a> 12.6mb</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/06/DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1.jpg" width="450" height="800" title="DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1" alt="DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1"></p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="http://danijelj.com/images/downloads/DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1.jpg">DJW.20160506.600D.0792.P1</a> 9.2mb</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[i will never stop fighting for love]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/03/i-will-never-stop-fighting-for-love/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-03T23:49:27+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/03/i-will-never-stop-fighting-for-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s not often that I will admit I make a mistake. I&rsquo;m a strong advocate for what I say being correct at the time and it should always continue to be correct because I said it. It&rsquo;s my belief. It&rsquo;s my virtue. It&rsquo;s my law.</p>

<p>A little while ago I met Jake. To be specific, I met him Saturday April 2<sup>nd</sup>. It was down in Semaphore under the clock tower <em>(now referred to as Jake &amp; Danijel&rsquo;s Clock Tower)</em>. Since that day my life has changed in a miraculous way that and I&rsquo;ve found the only man who has ever made time stand still every time I klep eyes on him. Without question, I have never understood the words <em>&ldquo;&hellip;fall in love in slow motion&rdquo;</em> until now.</p>

<p>One day since that time until now, Jake asked me a question. A simple question that I took not even more than a moment to reflex an answer from my values.</p>

<blockquote><p>Would you fight for me ?</p></blockquote>

<p>To go back in history, I&rsquo;d like to touch on a story about my great aunty and her husband. I don&rsquo;t recall the exact details but I&rsquo;d very much like to touch on this subject with her one day soon so I can capture the words myself and keep them safe to remind people that love like in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Notebook_(2004_film)">The Notebook</a> does exist in real life, and people can have it if you open your heart to it.</p>

<p>My great aunty was engaged to another man. Weeks before she was to be married, another man came by her and asked her for a date. She politely declined as she was already engaged to someone else. Not willing to take no for an answer, the man asked her the date. With a few weeks until she said &ldquo;I do&rdquo; with someone else he told her that he had that many weeks then to convince her that he was the better choice and she should marry him, because he felt more strongly for her.</p>

<p>I remember my mum quoting my great uncle saying something like:</p>

<blockquote><p>Don&rsquo;t marry him, marry me. I&rsquo;m better than him. I&rsquo;ll love you better and you&rsquo;ll never be unhappy with me in your life. I&rsquo;ll show you the greatest love you can ever have.</p></blockquote>

<p>So what did he do ? He fought for her love. We live in a day and age when you can say there&rsquo;s not such thing as <em>&ldquo;love at first sight&rdquo;</em> but I tend to disagree strongly. He obviously felt like he was in love with her the moment he saw her and I can attest to the love they had lasted many years all through my youth and she loved him too until the day he died.</p>

<p>He fought. For her love. And he won. He fought every day for her love. And he won every day that he fought that battle. And my great aunty ne'er regret a single day by choosing the man who was my great uncle. I always admired their love. It was so strong and potent right to the last time they kissed each other goodnight for the endless sleep.</p>

<p>Before you wonder, yes - writing about this brings tears to my eyes. Tears of joy and happiness. I could write articles of the love between all the members of my family that I&rsquo;ve grown up with, including my parents. <em>(That&rsquo;s a story for another time !)</em></p>

<p>So then, you&rsquo;ll probably be wondering how did I answer Jake ? In the most notably ineffective way ever. Absolutely ever !</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been in a number of relationships that are both long and short, some that even spanned across states. And what did I learn from all these relationships from the past ? Something not great. I generated a reflex action that if someone wants to leave me; I let them go. But why you might ask ? Simple - I&rsquo;m here. They&rsquo;re there. They want to go, let them go. Celebrate what you had while it&rsquo;s there and enjoy it for the moment. Don&rsquo;t hold on to what you don&rsquo;t have.</p>

<p>👆 That there, is the worst advice I have ever given, to anyone or myself. Love is not expendable. If you can dispense with your love for someone; then they deserve to be with someone better - you never really truly loved them.</p>

<p>Once upon a time, a friend of mine who can see clearly to the core of who I am said to me:</p>

<blockquote><p>You are never truly in love with someone. You just accept them as the current person in your life.</p></blockquote>

<p>And you know what ? That person was correct. 100% correct. I never truly fell in love with anyone that was in my life. I generated a reflex action to a situation and added that to the core of my beliefs and behaviours. You could even refer to them as <em>&ldquo;The Laws of Danijel&rdquo;</em> which I live vehemently by, everyday of my life.</p>

<p>So without a moment&rsquo;s hesitation, I jerked into my usual reflex and answered his question in the most poor of methods. And it&rsquo;s stuck with me since then how I answered. Did I really believe what I was saying ? Why was it resounding in my memory ? Why was my dreams plagued with this question ? What was going on ?</p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t believe it. Not one word. Nothing. It was all wrong. All of it !</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t let Jake walk out of my life. Not without a fight. Not at all. I&rsquo;m going to fight for him until my last breath. When I stop, it&rsquo;s because he&rsquo;s not reacting to me anymore and our love has died. I can&rsquo;t resuscitate something from the dead once it&rsquo;s gone for good.</p>

<p>Taking into consideration that I&rsquo;m going to fight, I need to elaborate why I&rsquo;m going to give it my all.</p>

<h3>Falling in love requires giving someone permission to break your heart.</h3>

<p>I have a special tattoo on my chest that is placed right over my heart. It&rsquo;s a Hōmonka (蜂紋華) which to me, represents <em>death in two steps</em>.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/04/02/20160402.iPhone6Plus.133041.jpg" width="600" height="800" title="Hōmonka (蜂紋華)" alt="death in two steps"></p>

<p>The first step to the death of your heart <em>(love)</em> is the giving of your heart to someone. You don&rsquo;t have to give it whole, just a part of it. You sneak away into their soul and hide a small piece in the depths they never knew existed. There it stays forever. If there ever comes a time when the two of you walk away from each other, the second step is enacted and your heart&rsquo;s death will be sudden and the second step is complete.</p>

<p>I will never let Jake walk away with that piece of my heart in his soul without fighting for it. I&rsquo;ve given him permission to break my heart, but I don&rsquo;t want this to ever happen without giving it my all. For the first time ever in my life, I&rsquo;ve used my ninja skills to sneak into his soul and put a small piece of myself there that I don&rsquo;t want returned.</p>

<h3>The only love worth having is the love worth fighting for.</h3>

<p>There was a time not too long ago Jake had a bad day and said he was going to run away to Antartica. At that moment my heart stopped. It really hurt. I did a drawing with an arrow pointing to me and another with my representation of Antartica asking him if he chose me, or Antartica.</p>

<p>He chose me.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/04/05/20160405.iPhone5Plus.003021.jpg" width="800" height="800" title="antartica lost to me" alt="antartica lost to me"></p>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t know what I would do next. If Jake hadn&rsquo;t chosen me, I quickly needed to find a way to prove to him I was the better choice. I wasn&rsquo;t going to give up that easily. Every single word in his response was going to touch me. I wanted to not let this go. Did I need to press rewind and go back to fix something ? Not this time. Not ever. I&rsquo;m not going to regret what I&rsquo;ve done, but I will make damned sure I do it right in the future.</p>

<p>The next image I sent him was me pointing my tongue at the penguin <em>(above)</em>, because I&rsquo;d won this round, and I was going to win every round from today until the day I kiss him my last goodnight.</p>

<h3>If I don&rsquo;t fight for it, I don&rsquo;t want it bad enough.</h3>

<p>Every single day I say good morning and I say goodnight. He&rsquo;s worth the blessings I give him. I want him to have a good day and a good night. It&rsquo;s not about what I can take from Jake, it&rsquo;s about what I can give Jake.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/05/04/20160504.jakes_goodnight.jpg" width="492" height="800" title="goodnight and sweet dreams jake" alt="goodnight and sweet dreams jake"></p>

<p>I want him. Every day. Every night. I want Jake in my life. I&rsquo;m going to show him this with every step of the way.</p>

<h3>If you love someone, let them go. If they return, they were always yours. If they don’t, they never were</h3>

<p>It&rsquo;s not true.</p>

<p>Jake is the person that fills my heart with happiness and love. Doesn’t he deserve to be fought for ? Wouldn’t I want him to fight to keep me ? If he’s worth spending your life with, he’s worth fighting for!</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/04/30/20160430.iPhone6Plus.112909.jpg" width="481" height="800" title="jake will be my husband one day" alt="jake will be my husband one day"></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not over until I&rsquo;ve decided to let go. Just because Jake one day might say goodbye to me, it doesn&rsquo;t mean it&rsquo;s over. It just means I have even more of an incentive to fight for him. As long as I hold but don&rsquo;t keep fighting, it&rsquo;s not really love. As long as I still love him, I won&rsquo;t let the relationship be over, ever.</p>

<h3>If I wasn&rsquo;t willing to fight for it, then I&rsquo;m sorry&hellip;but Jake deserves better than me.</h3>

<p>And this is the truth that I will settle on. I was wrong. I&rsquo;m not going to let him go without making an effort. He&rsquo;s magical. I love all of him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[legacy java 6 runtime]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/02/legacy-java-6-runtime/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-02T11:43:44+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/02/legacy-java-6-runtime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Java for OS X 2015-001 installs the legacy Java 6 runtime for OS X 10.11 El Capitan, OS X 10.10 Yosemite, OS X 10.9 Mavericks, OS X 10.8 Mountain Lion, and OS X 10.7 Lion.</p>

<p>This package is exclusively intended for support of legacy software and installs the same deprecated version of Java 6 included in the 2014-001 and 2013-005 releases.</p>

<p>Quit any Java applications before installing this update.</p>

<p><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="http://support.apple.com/downloads/DL1572/en_US/javaforosx.dmg">http://support.apple.com/downloads/DL1572/en_US/javaforosx.dmg</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[restore deleted brew formula]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/01/restore-deleted-brew-formula/"/>
    <updated>2016-05-01T01:06:49+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/05/01/restore-deleted-brew-formula</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Totally fucked up tonight by deleting Caskroom formula from the system.</p>

<p>Running <code>brew update</code> gave me the following error message:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="p">|</span> <span class="o">=</span>&gt; brew update
</span><span class='line'>To restore the stashed changes to /usr/local/Library/Taps/caskroom/homebrew-cask run:
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="s1">&#39;cd /usr/local/Library/Taps/caskroom/homebrew-cask &amp;&amp; git stash pop&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>Already up-to-date.
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So I do what it asks, then this pops up:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>On branch master
</span><span class='line'>Your branch is up-to-date with <span class="s1">&#39;origin/master&#39;</span>.
</span><span class='line'>Changes not staged <span class="k">for</span> commit:
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">(</span>use <span class="s2">&quot;git add/rm &lt;file&gt;...&quot;</span> to update what will be committed<span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">(</span>use <span class="s2">&quot;git checkout -- &lt;file&gt;...&quot;</span> to discard changes in working directory<span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    deleted:    Casks/itsycal.rb
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>no changes added to commit <span class="o">(</span>use <span class="s2">&quot;git add&quot;</span> and/or <span class="s2">&quot;git commit -a&quot;</span><span class="o">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>To repair this got a list of the taps in brew:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="p">|</span> <span class="o">=</span>&gt; brew tap
</span><span class='line'>caskroom/cask
</span><span class='line'>homebrew/completions
</span><span class='line'>homebrew/core
</span><span class='line'>homebrew/fuse
</span><span class='line'>homebrew/games
</span><span class='line'>homebrew/python
</span><span class='line'>homebrew/science
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Re-tapped the <code>caskroom/cask</code> tap:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="p">|</span> <span class="o">=</span>&gt; brew tap caskroom/cask
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Then I reinstalled ityscal again:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="p">|</span> <span class="o">=</span>&gt; brew cask install <span class="nv">itsycal</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">==</span>&gt; Downloading https://s3.amazonaws.com/itsycal/Itsycal-0.10.12.zip
</span><span class='line'><span class="c">######################################################################## 100.0%</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">==</span>&gt; Verifying checksum <span class="k">for</span> Cask <span class="nv">itsycal</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">==</span>&gt; Symlinking App <span class="s1">&#39;Itsycal.app&#39;</span> to <span class="s1">&#39;/Users/danijel.james/Applications/Itsycal.app&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>🍺  itsycal staged at <span class="s1">&#39;/opt/homebrew-cask/Caskroom/itsycal/0.10.12&#39;</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="m">189</span> files, 3.7M<span class="o">)</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>To run a fix across all your taps <em>(you might not know which one is causing the problems)</em>, just tap into all the taps again:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span> i in <span class="k">$(</span>brew tap<span class="k">)</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">do</span> brew tap <span class="s2">&quot;$i&quot;</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">done</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This one liner is your life saver. 😉</p>

<p>Problem solved !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[update brew cask pkgs]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/27/update-brew-cask-pkgs/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-27T11:03:52+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/27/update-brew-cask-pkgs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Update brew packages:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>brew update
</span><span class='line'>brew upgrade
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Update brew &amp; cask packages:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="c">#!/usr/bin/env bash</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>brew update
</span><span class='line'>brew cask update
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nv">casks</span><span class="o">=(</span> <span class="k">$(</span>brew cask list<span class="k">)</span> <span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span> cask in <span class="k">${</span><span class="nv">casks</span><span class="p">[@]</span><span class="k">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="c"># in the first line there is version</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nv">current</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&quot;$(brew cask info $cask | sed -n &#39;1p&#39; | sed -n &#39;s/^.*: \(.*\)$/\1/p&#39;)&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nv">installed</span><span class="o">=(</span> <span class="k">$(</span>ls /opt/homebrew-cask/Caskroom/<span class="nv">$cask</span><span class="k">)</span><span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="o">(</span>! <span class="o">[[</span> <span class="s2">&quot; ${installed[@]} &quot;</span> <span class="o">==</span> *<span class="s2">&quot; $current &quot;</span>* <span class="o">]])</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">then</span>
</span><span class='line'>        <span class="o">(</span><span class="nb">set</span> -x<span class="p">;</span> brew cask install <span class="nv">$cask</span> --force<span class="p">;</span><span class="o">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">fi</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">done</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>brew upgrade
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Reinstall brew &amp; cask packages:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'><span class="c">#!/usr/bin/env bash</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>rm -rf <span class="s2">&quot;$(brew --cache)&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>brew update
</span><span class='line'>brew cask update
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">for</span> app in <span class="k">$(</span>brew cask list<span class="k">)</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>  brew cask install --force <span class="s2">&quot;${app}&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">done</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>brew upgrade
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><strong>source:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/caskroom/homebrew-cask/issues/309">https://github.com/caskroom/homebrew-cask/issues/309</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[sunrise from mt lofty house]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/26/sunrise-from-mt-lofty-house/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-26T11:16:54+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/26/sunrise-from-mt-lofty-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wasn&rsquo;t feeling well on the weekend and so my dear brought me dinner last night and a random visit which seemed to <em>bump</em> me back into life and get me happy and alive again. No longer do I look or feel like death reheated.</p>

<p>Not sure how to repay my dear, so I got up at 5:30 in the morning and went to Mt Lofty to see where I could find an amazing vantage point for the sunrise.</p>

<p>I discovered <a href="http://www.mtloftyhouse.com.au">Mount Lofty House</a>. I might have to plan a secret weekend getaway for the two of us up there sometime in the folding cold of winter and steal my dear away.</p>

<p><img src="http://danijelj.com/images/2016/04/26/20160426.iPhone6plus.0995.jpg" width="800" height="324"  alt="sunrise from Mt Lofty House on Tuesday"></p>

<p>Captured three images, this is the low-res version of one of them.</p>

<p>Good morning everyone !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[generate checksums]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/23/generate-checksums/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-23T21:56:38+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/23/generate-checksums</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Bash</h3>

<p>Calculate MD5 checksum:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>md5 /tmp/1.iso
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Calculate SHA-1 checksum:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>shasum -a <span class="m">1</span> /tmp/1.iso
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Calculate SHA-256 checksum:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>shasum -a <span class="m">256</span> /tmp/1.iso
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[common string literals and operations]]></title>
    <link href="http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/20/common-string-literals-and-operations/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-20T11:31:40+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://danijelj.com/blog/2016/04/20/common-string-literals-and-operations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Python string basics. Useful as a reminder to myself. Sometimes I forget this kind of basic stuff and end up writing whole methods that don&rsquo;t need to be created.</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left;"> Operation </th>
<th style="text-align:left;"> Interpretation </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">K = &lsquo;&rsquo; </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Empty string </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">K = &ldquo;eggs&rsquo;s&rdquo; </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Double quotes, same as single </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">K = &rsquo;s\nu\tga\x00r' </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Escape sequences </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">K = &ldquo;&rdquo;&ldquo;&hellip;multiline&hellip;&rdquo; </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Triple-quoted block strings </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">K = r'\temp\eggs' </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Raw strings (no escapes) </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">C = c'sp\xc4m' </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Byte strings in 2.6, 2.7, and 3.X </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">U = u'sp\u00c4m' </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Unicode strings in 2.X and 3.3+ </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">T1 + T2 </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Concatenate </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">L * 3 </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Repeat </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">L[i] </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Index </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">L[i:j] </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Slice </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">len(L) </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Length </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">&ldquo;a %s joke&rdquo; % funny </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> String formatting expresion </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">&ldquo;a {0} joke&rdquo;.format(funny) </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> String formatting method in 2.6, 2.7 and 3.X </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">G.find(&lsquo;ake&rsquo;) </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> String method </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">for i in G: print(i) </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Iteration </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">&lsquo;ake&rsquo; in J </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Membership </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left;">[ i * 2 for i in J ] </td>
<td style="text-align:left;"> Iteration </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<hr>


<p><em>Attribution: Learning Python, Mark Lutz 978-1-449-35573-9</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
